[music]
Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
>> Hey,
hey, hey. [music]
Heat. Heat.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat. Hey, heat. Hey, heat.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat.
[music]
Heat.
[music] Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Welcome Living Mana Church family. It's
so good to see you here today. You are
here to worship God together uh with
your church family. And we are so happy
to have you here with us today. Please
put in the chat where you're viewing
from. We want to say a special welcome
to you. If you can put your name and
where you're viewing from because
sometimes your handles that you have
don't have your name, but if you could
put your name and where you're viewing
from, that would be wonderful. And if
this is your very first time, please put
a one in the chat. We want to that means
you're if this is your first time again,
please put a one. We want to do a
special welcome to you. And I think I
saw the very first person, there's a lot
of you talking in the chat, but the
first person said they are viewing from
Brooklyn, New York. And so, welcome. And
please, all of the rest of you, please
put in the chat where you're viewing
from. So, again, we can say a special
welcome to you.
>> Absolutely. We um and we are glad to be
back home.
>> Back home
>> once again.
>> Home. Yay.
>> Uh we were uh on the road for a couple
of weeks.
>> Well, and and the the funny thing
[clears throat] is is that we were on
the road for a couple of weeks, but it
was like we went for Christmas, came
home for four days,
>> our daughter went into labor, we went
back and was there for a week. So, it
was like we were almost there for three
weeks or two and a half, but we
>> Yeah. But it was great to be with our
children and grandchildren.
>> And uh it is and it is also nice to be
back.
>> It's also nice to be back home. Yeah.
It's always nice to be back home
>> studio.
>> Yes. And with all of you.
>> Yeah.
So uh again, welcome everyone. We want
to wish you a um a happy Sabbath. We
want to welcome you to Living Mana
Online Church. And um I believe as usual
the Lord has a powerful
tasty mana in store for us today.
>> And um
that's uh I think that's one of the
things that people appreciate about uh
living mana is the title really speaks
to what you know the Lord gives us here
at this church.
>> The title of our church. The name of our
church. Yeah. Living mana. Fresh.
>> Fresh.
>> Fresh bread.
>> Fresh bread. Yummy bread. Tasty bread.
>> Tasty bread. [laughter]
>> Amen.
>> Yes. All right. Just want to say uh
welcome to I think Wendy from Idaho.
Welcome. Good to see you here. Uh we
have Jacob from Paradise, California.
Good to see you here. Uh Jacob also
looks like we have uh I think Ginger
from New York City. We have quite a few
from New York, which is wonderful. Um,
we have rain from Minnesota. Um, hope
you're staying warm and safe in
Minnesota. Rain. Lots of things
happening there. Um, let's
[clears throat] see.
All right, we have um we have John
Heasley from MacArthur, Ohio. Always
good to see you, John. Welcome. We have
um we have Oregon here. Welcome Ayana
from Trinidad and Tobago. Always good to
see you. Here we have our dear friend
from Serbia. I say friend from East
Europe, Serbia because I I see you here
often. I don't know your name though.
So, please put in the chat what your
name is from East Europe, Serbia. But we
welcome you and it's good to see you
here as well. Keith and Joanne from
Barbados. Good to see you guys here.
Also, let's see. We had a one. We had a
one. Oh boy. I saw the one and now I
don't see the one, but I'm going to find
the one. And maybe So, we have All
right. We have
someone from I don't know how to
pronounce this. From Le Oh, man. Letho
Masura.
>> I can't even see see where you're
looking.
>> Okay. It's the only one. Yeah. if you if
you want to help me pronounce it
correctly because I know I did not. Um
and I just don't know where that it
where that is.
Okay. So, I don't know if it's near Ser.
Well, you can put in the chat. I think
it's under where you're where you're
looking, but we're well we're happy that
you are here. We're happy that you are
here and that this is your very first
time. So we are uh officially an online
church and so we have programming all
throughout the week and we have programs
on mental health on Mondays, we have uh
physical health on Tuesday, we have two
prayer services on Wednesday and so we
are just so we are here all throughout
the all throughout the week and then we
have many small groups that you can join
and be a part of and so we are a very
active I want to say loving church. just
ended the 10 days of prayer that the
worldwide church uh was doing and I just
could unfortunately I was only able to
be present at three of the days which
you know what that was probably like my
first time and with that just only three
three days um that because you know
Operation Global Rain started in 2007
and then the worldwide church took it
over and made it the 10 days of prayer
[snorts] so that's many years that I've
been attending the 10 days of prayer for
our 7th Day Adventist church, but this
time it was only three times, guys, and
last night was the third. But I heard
all the love um and the wonderful
fellowship and the blessing that the 10
days of prayer always brings to people.
They always feel changed. Sometimes it's
a daunting task to be like, "Oh, I'm
going to get together with my church for
10 days in a row." But I always always
um the testimonies coming out of it are
true blessings. Even one year, do you
remember that year in Templeton? It was
the 10 days of prayer and then we did an
allnight
>> prayer meeting. That was amazing. Yeah,
>> it was absolutely amazing. Like the 10
days of prayer went to an all night
prayer.
>> Um and what we did for church service
that day I remember is we just had
testimonies for the sermon. Yeah.
>> People just testified of what Jesus did
for them during that
>> not just for during the all night prayer
that too, but during the 10 days. Yeah.
>> And it was just it was just like the
most incredible Sabbath. So anyways,
>> that was a blessing. So just to let you
know that's who we are uh the person
that's here for the first time and we're
just thankful uh that you are here and
you'll get more information about the
church uh during uh the welcome during
the divine worship service. So
>> and brother Spamco, I see you uh and uh
brother John, send me a text. Let's
connect this week for sure. All right.
Um,
and so yeah, greetings to everyone.
Everyone, everyone.
>> Yes, greetings. Have those from South
Carolina, North Carolina. I'm just
seeing more people. More Brooklyn, New
York.
>> We We have We have a quite a We have a
great presence in New York. I have to
say, our New York family,
>> they show up. They're real. They're here
every week.
>> Yeah.
>> From all the different burrows and
>> uh upstate everywhere.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> Yep.
>> Praise God.
Praise God. All right. Did you want to
talk about last night a little bit
before you go to my shirt?
>> We can talk about last night. This is
just um uh H
>> John says he doesn't have your number,
but Okay, John. Um
we'll get you.
>> Okay, John. We'll figure it out. We'll
figure it out
>> through Mighty Networks. Like message
each other through Mighty Networks. That
would be good to get each other's
numbers. Um, so last night, uh, Power of
the Land Ministries, uh, went live.
Um, and, uh, we
we talked about they're pronouncing the
Lut
in Southern Africa.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I was reading that,
too. And they were saying, "Thanks. If
it's okay if you can't pronounce it,
it's African country." Okay. They said
their their friends will have a good
laugh. Okay. Okay. I'm glad I can make
your friends laugh. Well, welcome from a
country in Africa that I've never heard
of before. Okay. I've heard of many
countries. Okay. Welcome. We're so happy
that you are here and that you found us.
>> So, yeah.
>> All right. So, um
last night we did a special message on
the T horns
>> of um
>> that I never understood before. The ten
horns is like,
>> "Yeah,
>> oh, they don't really mean anything." I
mean, when does something in the Bible
not really mean anything?
That was dumb of me.
>> Yeah.
>> But uh we had a two-hour presentation on
uh this subject of the 10 horns
>> and uh if you have not uh seen it yet, I
definitely want to encourage you to go
uh check it out. Um it is uh really eye
opening. It is really uh I think
speaks a lot to what is going on today
in our country. Yes, absolutely.
>> Um, particularly within Christianity
here in America.
>> Uh, and some of you are saying, I see
one person saying they just watched this
morning on what just watched this
morning.
>> A lot of people watching in the middle
of night. The numbers doubled and
tripled in the middle of the night. I
was like, yeah,
>> other people in other countries were
definitely watching while we were
sleeping.
>> Um, but uh yeah, definitely check it out
uh if you get a chance.
>> Um, because uh it'll it'll
help you understand a subject. Like I
was saying last night
in almost every presentation I've ever
heard on Daniel 7 and I've ever given on
Daniel 7. Um
it's been the the common theme is okay.
So there were 10 horns that came out of
out of um the fallen Roman Empire.
>> Three of them were uprooted. Let's lock
in on the little horn because that's the
real focus
>> of Daniel chapter 7. [clears throat] Um,
and that's how I've taught it. That's
how I've heard it.
>> Everybody,
>> that's how Yeah, it it it is rare that
uh you'll find a study going into the
actual T horns. And
>> besides mentioning the names,
>> besides mentioning the names and who
they represent today,
>> that's it. That's as far as it went. And
it will I think it will help you to
understand
just how much God reveals in those ten
horns the history. Um it's it's really
amazing. It's really amazing. So um make
sure you check it out.
>> Yeah.
>> Make sure.
>> And it was like a very
>> easy follow. And I'm talking about for
myself. I mean, it would just made it
was really it was simple. The his it was
very I like the way you broke it down um
and just showed the consistency
um of what Satan was doing through all
of these horns and it just like the
thread just went through every single
>> Yeah.
>> um every single nation that
>> Yeah. it represents. So, it was very
easy.
>> Yeah. And I and I like what I'm just
reading here. Wes and I watched this
last night but started to rewatch it
over this morning. Wes had a very
profound thought about parts of the
video. Pastor, you should talk to Wes
about it.
>> You know, [clears throat]
one of the reasons that I was looking
forward to giving this presentation is
because this very thing right here,
right? [clears throat]
>> Knowing that other people
will go back, look at this study, and
then say, "Wait a minute. You know what?
If we look at this and kind of add to
>> because I've been studying this out for
the last this study has been on my I've
been studying this for the last um
>> probably a couple months longer.
>> No, no, it's probably actually it's been
about two months.
>> Yeah, cuz I remember when you first
brought
>> It's been about two months.
>> Um but I know that I really just
scratched the surface,
>> you know. So the way truth works is when
other people see things that when other
people hear or see,
>> they will think of things that you know
you weren't thinking about and be like,
"Did you realize X Y and Z?" And so I
think the way this study is going to
grow
>> and how it's going to really
>> just impact our understanding of of
history that unfolded throughout the
dark ages and how all those different
those 10 different versions will I'll
just kind of let a little bit out the
bag for those of you that that didn't
watch last night. These 10 horns
>> are going to watch.
>> Yeah. represent 10 different versions of
what happens when you mix iron and clay.
>> Yes.
>> Right. So there are 10 different
versions of let's just say counterfeit
or false Christianity.
>> Each one of those horns
is mingled with is iron mingled with
clay. M
>> and each one of them shows as you look
at the history of each of these horns
they are a revelation of this is what
happens when you mix Christianity and um
political power this is the result
>> right
>> so really eye opening but um yes Wes
reach out to me and let me know what
else you've seen and anybody else as
you're watching comment in the
>> in the in the in the uh comments comment
section
>> and um
>> yeah, I was just super excited to give
this. I've been waiting for two months
to give this study and you know,
different things have happened. We had
had to cancel a couple times because XY
>> grandb babies are being born, the
holidays,
>> but uh
>> I was excited to be able to do that
study last night and finally share um
share with uh you guys what the Lord had
been sharing with me.
>> So,
>> yes. and t-shirt message.
>> T-shirt message. Um,
[clears throat] where God guides, he
provides. Isaiah 58:11.
>> So, this is an oldie but goodie.
Um, this is definitely not the first
time I've worn this. Um, but it just
I like it's just a good reminder of the
fact that we don't have to worry about
anything.
>> He doesn't give us a spirit of fear. I'd
say he doesn't give us the spirit of
fear, which I was going to say doesn't
give us anxiety, which is fear. He
doesn't give us the spirit of worry,
which is fear. You know, he just we
don't we don't have to worry about
anything. We can say, God,
this is what I want to do. This is what
is on my heart, but I'm putting what's
on my heart in your hands. Mh.
>> And so whatever doors he opens or
closes, that is his will. And whatever
situation you're in where you're not
seeing something happening or you he
you're in a place and you don't know why
you're in a place, you don't have to
worry about how to maintain in that
place because wherever he has guided you
and opened that door, he will provide.
>> And we so we have nothing to worry
about. And the Bible's very clear. Our
worry does nothing. And our worry turns
into stress. Stress, I don't want to say
our worry does nothing. Our worry does
do something. It causes stress. Stress
which causes um damage to your mental
health along with your physical health.
And so um we can just trust God in any
situation throughout all things in our
life. No matter how big, how small, the
worry, the anxiety, the fear, all coming
from the same place. Uh it does nothing
but cause damage to your to you
physically um and to your mental health.
So just trust God.
>> Yeah.
>> All the time, every day. Just remind
him. I had a thing yesterday. Might as
well put a I had a thing. No, it started
Thursday night and I was just learning
something and I was like, okay. I
started to fear or worry because it's
like and then I was like I said, God,
no. You knew that I we I didn't know
anything about this and I can't I
couldn't do anything about something I
didn't know anything about and now I
know. So now I'm putting it in your
hands in the morning. I'm going to call
the proper people I need to call and I'm
just going to tell them the truth
because it's always you always have to
tell the truth if you want God to bless
you. You can't not you can't be
deceitful. And I just made the phone
call and within 10 15 minutes the person
was like oh you just do this this this
and this and that's will fix the
problem.
>> I was like thank you God. But I just
remember Thursday night being like, I'm
not going to worry about this and take
this to bed in my sleep. And you know
how you just sleep worried or whatever?
It's horrible sleep. Um, and I just I I
said that to God and he worked it out.
But he also gave me peace.
>> Amen.
>> So, that Sabbath school.
>> Sabbath school.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, we're going to go ahead and invite
our guests on and we need to pray.
>> Yeah, we need to pray. And we we have a
much smaller panel today, but that's
okay. Yes,
>> this is the panel God wanted for today.
>> Mhm.
>> Yes.
>> So, uh let's bring our guest on and then
we'll pray.
>> Yes.
>> Welcome guest.
[laughter]
>> Hey. Oh, look at you guys matching. You
guys are twinning. The pastor and the
prayer leader. Look at you guys.
Baldheads and everything. You got to put
your glasses on. I [laughter] You're
going to be a real twin.
>> Uh we can't hear you, Terry. So, I don't
know if everybody else can hear you, but
uh
>> Yes. And we need to hear him.
Oh, there we go. Mr. Mute. [laughter]
>> I
good to be here. And we were here last
week. We back in our studio, back in the
main studio. But it's good to see you,
too. It's good to see you and pastor uh
Twinning, maybe even me and Amra.
[laughter]
>> That's funny. [gasps]
>> Yeah. If people are just tuning in for
the first time, they're like, "Are they
brothers?" Because [laughter]
>> that's funny.
>> Actually, Terry looks like Ivor's oldest
or not oldest, second to oldest brother.
Yeah, definitely. Even Even Rowan. Okay,
that's that's his brother. But he said
at one time we were watching, we were in
Virginia and you were praying. He was
like, "He does look like me." [laughter]
So,
right.
>> Yes.
>> That's funny. That's funny. Um, so
Terry, I you know, we could hear you,
but they can't hear you. And I'm not
sure what what that's about. I'm not
sure how that's uh
>> how that's not either.
>> Yeah. So, uh, might be Yeah, it might be
something on the back end, but um,
>> that is Yeah. Okay. No audio for Terry,
guys. But can you hear us? Put a one in
the chat if you hear us. Okay. There's
the same brother Terry.
>> Yeah.
Oh, I don't know what to do. It looks
like I'm all I'm all good to go here.
>> Okay. So, we're going to let our team
work on that then. And just keep
listening to us, Terry. We're going to
pray. We're going to start and then when
you're up Yeah. Yeah.
>> And then we'll do some sound checks to
make sure you can they can hear you.
>> Okay, they can hear you now.
>> Oh, wonderful.
>> They can hear you now.
>> Okay, perfect.
>> Good, good, good.
>> Well, happy Sabbath, everyone.
[laughter]
>> Yeah, they they just missed our entire
conversation.
>> Terry's just happy that he can look like
pastor and that that him and that uh
pastor's uh older one of his ne not the
oldest, but the next oldest brother
looks like him and Terry look like Joe.
That's all you guys missed. That's all
we were saying.
All right.
>> Amen.
>> All right.
>> So, we're gonna we're gonna go ahead and
pray. Why don't we have Terry pray?
>> Yeah. Terry, could you could you lead us
in prayer?
>> Amen. Amen. Father, thank you again for
uh allowing us to be together here at
this wonderful Living Mana Online
Church. Thank you for everyone that's
watching. Thank you for Sabbath School.
and and Lord, we we are so um humbled
and excited about the way you've been
speaking to us through the word that's
been coming forth. Uh we want to open
our hearts and minds today and allow you
to continue to lead us and guide us.
Father, you are so good and pastor and
first lady reminded us of that last
night as we unfolded that amazing study
on the ten horns. Uh we know that it's
all connected and we are looking forward
to hearing what you have to say here
today. continue to bless, heal, touch,
save, and deliver as only you can do in
Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> All right. So, [clears throat]
>> um so I'm going to go ahead and we are
continuing guys on um the Christian art
of war. Uh we are going to be I think
wrapping up uh chapter 4. It has taken
us this long to get through chapter
four, but we do have breaks, so it's
understandable.
>> Um, so now I'm saying we're wrapping
>> and we miss our young voices today. Miss
everybody. We're going to miss our our
M&M's, but we're going to get them back.
>> Yeah. So, um,
like I said, I'm saying that we're going
to wrap up today on chapter 4.
>> We'll see.
>> But we just are not sure. We got three
sections left in chapter 4, but there
are three short sections. Okay. But
short sections just don't mean anything
when we're talking about
>> the fruit of the spirit. So,
>> and I want to say that you guys please
put in you're doing this study with us.
This is Sabbath school. So, please, you
know, if you have not um been able to
read through chapter 1 through 4, which
is on mighty networks. Please sign up
for Mighty Network so you can get that
or go to Mighty Networks if you are
signed up and look at those chapters. Um
but if you have, please comment with us.
Share your thoughts and feeling too. We
want to see your comments in the chat.
>> Amen.
>> And this is the book, The Christian Art
of War that Pastor wrote 17 years ago.
And uh we are going through it. We're
going through it again.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, all right.
>> And Clint, yeah, I just might do a part
two.
>> Clint is still stuck from last night.
And Clint was very active in the chat
last night. Clint, I saw you. I was
>> Clint is like our number one for mental
health Monday, but he's just a true
LMLC.
I might just do a part two. Okay, so we
are on the the final um well, we're on
the faith fighter section of the
Christian Art of War, chapter 4,
>> and we are looking at we've got the
faith fighters um or the the fruit of
faith and then meekness and then 10
principles is the last one. So, let me
go ahead and read uh
the section and this is entitled faith.
Um
>> I just want to do a plug
>> fighters.
>> Just do a plug really quick that someone
says, you know, they're just wondering
why we don't follow the quarterly. You
know, we do have an adult Sabbath school
um class that does follow the adult
quarterly Sabbath school guide for
Sabbath school. So, that is available
here at Living Matter Church as well.
>> Yeah. Um, so
faith fighters,
the spirit of faith is the spirit that
brings us in tune with the unseen. Now
faith is the substance of things hoped
for, the evidence of things not seen.
Hebrews 11:1.
This spirit grants us access into into
an unseen future. By this attribute, we
are empowered
um to base the logistics of our warfare
upon invisible realities and the
promises of God's word. Faith eliminates
the power visible the faith eliminates
the power visible appearance often have
over our courage and hope.
Um
we are called to fight the good fight of
faith. This is an invisible war, one
where we wrestle not against flesh and
blood, but against principalities,
against powers, against the rulers of
the darkness of this world, against
spiritual wickedness in high places.
Ephesians 6:12.
The warrior who has the spirit of faith
learns to fight blindfolded as it were.
He no longer needs eyes to see. Faith is
his eye.
2 Corinthians 5:7, for we For we walk by
faith, not by sight. He becomes a faith
fighter, one skilled in blind combat.
Therefore, darkness does not discourage
him.
Poor visibility because of the storm of
temptation does not trouble him.
Uh he is not afraid
of receiving bad news. His faith is
strong and he trusts in the Lord. That's
Psalms 112 verse7 uh the Good News
Bible.
Faith makes us invincible because our
minds are stayed upon the promises of
God. Like an invisible guiding system,
faith makes accurate our warfare,
leaving self-baffled and powerless to
stop our spiritual advances. Let us then
become experts in the spirit of faith
through the grace of God.
>> Okay.
>> Amen. that section on
>> on faith and we did we talked a little
bit about
>> um faith a little bit earlier because if
you remember I was given the example of
you know when my brother and I were
younger and how we would like train in
fighting
>> right how we would um and the rest of
our friends how we would blindfold
ourselves and then practice the martial
arts
>> right
>> blindfolded
>> with a wooden dummy
>> with a wooden dummy.
>> Um,
and there was uh
one game that we would like a exercise
we would play. We would tie we would get
a a rope
um and a tire
>> and we would basically be someone would
stand and just start
>> twirling the rope. So, we'd just be
spinning and so you got the tire out
there, the rope. They'd have to jump
over the rope
>> blindfolded. [laughter]
What?
>> So we were we were trying to hear the
sound of the tire.
>> You and Sean.
>> And and this is all of us, right? This
is like we're going to practice to
become the best martial artists ninjas
in the entire world.
>> Wow.
>> So we would just make stuff up like
that.
>> Right.
And I use that example
just to point out that
when you are learning to fight by faith,
>> the only thing you can depend on is your
hearing,
>> right?
>> Hearing the word God.
>> Because hearing, faith comes by hearing
>> and hearing by the word of God.
>> Yes. So
faith requires us to close our eyes.
>> All right? Because
>> Amen.
>> When you're when you see
>> what the devil's doing, when you see the
the calamity, the crisis, all these
things around you,
>> it is easy
>> to allow your eyes to tell you react
this way, react this way, right?
when the word of God is trying to tell
you
don't go by what you see go by what you
hear
>> because that's what he says in Hebrews
that you know faith is the evidence of
things not seen so he
>> God like
purposely I believe
doesn't allow things to happen to make
it seem like nothing's happening so you
can't see what he's really trying to do
at first so you can have faith and tell
it actually comes. You know what I'm
saying? Because
>> if he allowed things so clearly, if you
could see things so clearly, you
wouldn't have to practice any faith. You
wouldn't depend upon him. You wouldn't
call upon him. You would probably think
in our human sinful nature, we think we
did it.
>> But he puts us in positions to make sure
we know he did it.
>> Yeah.
>> So he doesn't He makes sure that we we
really don't see. Sometimes he'll give
us a little tidbit to be like or a
little something to keep us being like,
"Okay, God, you are working. It's not
the full thing, but okay, I can keep
trusting you. I can keep going."
>> But but he has to put us in situations
where we're blind where we're actually
spiritually blindfolded.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. And you know, it makes it easier
>> uh to deal with. It makes it a joy to
deal with when you know that's what he's
doing, right? You're
>> you're just thinking it a strange thing
concerning these fiery trials. You know
that God is actually training us, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And so I like I like that the the story
of the tire and and I got to think
about, you know, while you're trying to
tune your ears to be sensitive enough to
hear that tire coming.
>> You probably got down quite a few times
all upside the head and everything,
right? Trying trying [laughter] to
trying to dunk and catch that tire
coming, right? And I'm thinking about
it.
>> So surprising. That's so wild.
>> It is.
>> And that's the funny thing, man. It it
didn't we were just like, well, let's
just keep going.
>> When you're young and
>> you know, we have to become like just
like what we see in the martial arts
movies. So,
>> they thought they were ninjas.
>> Yeah. We are going to keep doing this.
>> Yeah. I love that. That's amazing. And
actually, I know people watch and I am
encouraged to think about, you know, the
trials I go through when God is saying,
Terry, I'm really trying to get your
hearing. You got to be able to hear me
because there's a lot going on and that
tire just coming.
>> I mean, how in the world are you going
to be sensitive enough to hear that tire
coming before you're on the ground again
getting dusty, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. and and powerful just
analogy that I'm just thinking of Terry
when you when you just did that is we
were literally listening for the sound
of the wind.
>> That's what we were doing
when that rope is cutting through the
air. You're hearing that
that might be a sermon title.
Wait a minute. [clears throat]
[laughter] What? What is that? How do
you spell?
We were listening for the wind
>> and
>> Amen.
>> Only when we heard the wind, you know,
okay, now now jump.
>> Right. And we weren't just jumping. We
were like, so this is in our backyard.
So we're diving doing front rolls. I
mean, we're not we're not just like jump
rope. I'm jumping. No, we had to do you
know trying to flip and my brother was
the flipper. So yeah, I was going to
say,
>> but diving and all the the the the the
somersaults and the
>> Yeah, we were crazy.
>> But
and I'll tell you what, it's kind of
funny as you think, you know, we would
watch these kung fu movies and like we
want to be this. And the way they would
train in these movies, right, Terry? You
you know, the way they would train in
these movies was like what? You know, a
guy with a pole having to mix soup.
>> Master, why am I mixing soup? [laughter]
Mix mix. And he would just be there for
>> for months and years mixing soup with a
pole. Why? Because when he's going to
translate that into real life, he
becomes skilled with the pole,
>> you know. Or jumping with with with uh
ankle weights on
>> and they would just spend hours jumping
jumping and then In the movie, they take
off the ankle weights and they're flying
>> and me and my brother at like 9 10 11
like we will fly too,
>> right?
>> We're going to fly.
>> Amen.
>> So,
>> just, you know, again, learning those
ways of of like, how can I train
>> to become a faith warrior? How can I
train to to listen to the sound of the
wind?
And that's really what what faith
fighting, right, is all about. Being
able to hear the sound of the wind
>> when it blows. And Jesus said, you know,
except, we talked about it last week,
right? Except to be born of the spirit.
>> And then he says, you know, the wind
bloweth where it lives, you cannot tell
whether it goes, where it's coming from
or where it goes,
>> but you hear the sound.
>> Lord, teach us to hear the sound.
uh of the wind so that we can learn to
respond to that sound.
>> And the wind represents the Holy Spirit
>> and the wind is the Holy Spirit
>> and it speaks to
>> Oh, go ahead, Terry.
>> Well, first lady, you you you said
something earlier and I think we all
sort of touched on it during the 10 days
of prayer. We know that God wants to
unleash his rushing mighty wind, the
wind of his spirit on the earth, right?
>> Especially in this time that we're
living in now. and and so he wants to
use us to do it. But we are so
accustomed to depending on the resources
of you know what we can see with our
eyes, what we can uh depend upon in in
everyday life. We've learned how to
depend on the resources of this world,
but um what is it that's keeping us from
being unleashed? We know God wants to.
And so each of us as we're praying and
seeking guidance and Lord, what is it
inside of me that's standing in the way
of you using me that way? And and you
know, I think we're all coming to the
conclusion that, you know, God, you're
teaching us through these trials,
through these challenges, through these
blindfolds when we don't see the answer.
We don't know which way it's coming
from. When where's your blessing coming?
Emmer and I are currently in the middle
of a storm even right now in our life.
And we're trusting the principle of
faith. God, we know you're gonna come
through
>> and you're not showing us because if you
did, we'd probably mess with it and mess
it all up, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And uh
>> so we're depending on him.
>> I like what you said right now.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. But we feel the peace of God and
we're thankful because we see him
moving.
>> Exactly. You can't see it, but he's
working. And it's kind of like I don't
know if you've ever been I mean this is
>> um maybe this is a me thing. I don't
know if all women are like this but when
I'm like in the kitchen and working and
cooking I don't need like I don't want a
whole bunch of people like staring and
looking. I'm working. I'm getting it all
done right. I'm getting the food. I'm
getting everything ready. Like just go
sit down and enjoy something like have a
snack or whatever while I'm doing this.
So I kind of just think like it's that's
how God is. It's like he doesn't want us
like looking at all the things that he's
actually doing. So, he has us
blindfolded, but he's working, but we're
just blindfolded. So,
>> we just need to sit down and and wait
until the meal is served, which is the
miracle that he's going to do for you
and Amra and what he does for all of us.
That's happening. He's in the kitchen
right now.
>> That's pretty That's That's pretty good.
You I never looked at it that way, but
that's pretty good. Let Let God cook.
>> Yeah. Let God cook.
>> Let Let him cook, as they say.
>> Get out of the way. Let
>> get out of the way. That might be
another ser, you know. I just I just
That's another sermon title right there.
>> You need to start writing these down
because I think you kind of forget.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
>> Let him cook.
>> Yeah. That's
>> when Amate and Terry's miracle happens.
Then you'll preach that the next week.
>> Let him cook.
>> That's going to be the sermon.
>> Oh Lord. Yeah.
Um,
you know, I was thinking about um
Samson
and how
uh
God had to bring him to a place of
blindness
for him to finally hear.
>> God had to bring him to a place of
blindness for him to finally hear.
>> Yeah. And um
you know in that blindness he's learning
how to be a faith fighter,
>> right?
>> Uh so I think sometimes God
allows us
uh to
to be blind in order to teach us how to
how to live by faith, how to live by
hearing. Because how many of us have
gone through a situation where
>> you know we cannot understand
>> and that's what's seeing is
understanding. When someone says, "Oh, I
see now."
>> Right? You're saying, "Oh, I
understand."
>> So if we take away sight, that's
symbolically speaking, "I don't
understand. Why would this happen? Lord,
how is this happening? I don't
understand. I follow you,
>> you know. I'm I'm I'm I believe in you.
Why is this happening? How did this
happen? We can't see. We can't
understand." And I think sometimes
again, God allows us
to go through these periods of
>> blindness.
Um, yeah, man. Third angel 14:12. I was
just thinking about that verse. Isaiah
42:19. Who is blind but my servant? Or
deaf as my messenger that I sent? Who is
blind as he that is perfect and blind as
the Lord's servant?
>> How blind.
>> Amen.
>> Yeah.
>> What what is this verse talking about?
And what is literally telling us
speaking of Jesus is that Jesus was
blind and deaf to insult.
>> He was blind and deaf to
>> to the obstacles like,
>> you know, no, you can't do this or
>> he was blind to that. So
>> God is calling us
>> to be blind
>> and to be deaf
>> towards every whisper of the enemy,
>> every obstacle he pre he presents before
us.
[clears throat]
>> I mean in one imagine walking through
life blind
>> and deaf.
>> Wow. Wow. Wow. I
>> Why aren't you offended about what she
said? About what he said?
>> What did they say?
>> I [laughter] didn't I didn't hear it,
but she just said it to your face.
I didn't hear it.
>> Yeah. Wow.
>> Amen. I'm also um I'm probably like a
lot of our viewers and our church
members who are watching are still
kind of tasting that tasty mana from
last night.
>> Uh the story of the horns. I have not
been able to stop thinking about it
>> and seeing the connection for it.
>> Story of the what, Terry?
>> The ten horns.
>> Okay.
>> Oh, the ten horns. Like you said, the
orange.
>> And so this just this morning I got I
was looking again at the title faith
fighters of his faith section. Mhm.
>> And the way you talked about the T horns
and how we went to Revelation 7, we saw
how these kings will have their power
prolonged for one hour with the beast,
you know, how how the mingling of the
iron and the clay. We were really seeing
that final hour all of this is going to
be manifested at one time,
>> right?
And it took me back and and even today
you're talking about the house of David.
When you preached the sermon on Goliath
and he went through all the metals, it
made me realize, wow, David's looking at
all of these kingdoms and everything did
at one time in this one giant.
>> And so for us to be able to stand in
that final hour, we're going to have to
be some real faith fighters.
>> Yeah.
>> We won't be able to depend on anything
in this world. We're going to need
something supernatural to stand against
that giant
>> in that 10th hour.
>> And listen,
>> because last night I was sitting there
thinking, "Oh my Lord,
>> what are we gonna do?" And somebody even
put it in the chat, "What do we do now?
>> What do we do now?"
>> And we have we got to tap into that
supernatural power. Jesus has got to be
real. The miracle working power has to
be real. I've got to be sold out. And so
>> yeah, I mean,
>> powerful stuff. God is saying to us.
>> Yeah. It's funny because uh in my sermon
today, the house of David,
um it kind of has everything to do with
what you just said
>> and we're kind of going to be talking
about that last generation again. Mhm.
>> Um [clears throat]
but it is
if we think about
living just in the time of one of those
previous horns,
>> which is what you're saying, Terry,
right?
>> Just think about living in the time of
the of the uh of the uh Swaya or the
Visiggoth horn, which would be Spain.
>> Just Imagine
living in that time and then multiply
that by 10
>> because now you got 10 different horns,
right? With 10 different scenarios. All
of that combined in one
that final 10th
>> horn that final
hour.
>> Um
>> yeah. Wow.
you know,
>> just an unbelievable connection, pastor.
>> I mean, the way the spirit of God
brought that study out,
>> um, you were able to make us see, help
us to see why Jesus said it will be a
time like nothing.
>> Yeah.
>> Any generation has ever known in this
world.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, a time that has never been
before it or never be after it. that you
know and you know I love the way you
guys said you know in the at the end you
know God is good for showing us this
>> right he showed us this ahead of time so
that we could get ready and we could be
prepared and so the time of training and
fighting blindfolded we think some of
our everyday trial that we're going
through now Lord help me to get through
this and we often hear saints say well
if you can't go with the footman how you
going to roll with the horsemen you know
we always hear that quote but in reality
the beautiful thing is God is saying,
"Hey, I'm training you guys. I'm
training you
>> not to depend on uh resources of this
world when you've got a a government
that's saying, "Well, we have the right
to take everything you have."
>> Yeah.
>> If you're not of faith, you know, or you
have the we have the right to see you
suffer and die if you're not of this
particular bloodline. I mean, you think
about it. Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> We really got to know who we are.
>> Yep. Yep. You know, it's interesting.
Someone had put a little bit earlier.
Um, you know, Pastor Mer's mom must have
been a mom of faith with all that stuff
going on in the backyard.
>> That's funny. Yeah.
>> Um, [laughter]
>> definitely.
>> You know, and I I looked at the
statement and I and I kind of laughed at
it and then I was just like, you know,
it's it's kind of weird how not weird,
but it's not coincidental.
Um everything as I look back at my life,
everything the the things we practiced,
the things we did,
>> you know, from me, you know, like
writing music,
>> um my you know, martial arts,
>> um
just like every aspect, everything that
I was practicing
from a child growing up to my teenage
years to my Yeah. to my young adult
years.
I'm looking back and I'm like, "Wow, the
Lord the Lord was training me."
>> Um,
even though that, you know, I'm not
saying that all the things I was doing
were necessarily whatever good, but
>> but he was using things
>> he was using things
>> to prepare me,
>> right? Oh, you want to be a fighter? You
wanna you want, you know, you want to
beat up 20 people at a time, you want to
be the martial artist. I'm gonna show
you [laughter] the martial artist that I
want you to be. Right?
>> You want to write music, you want to
write lyrics that are gonna make people
be like, "Wow, what did he just I'm
going to show you the lyricist that I
want you to be." So, every area
in in your life, it's like God is using
that to prepare you for something
greater,
>> right? And in the same way I think the
things that we go through you know as
his people even though we may not
understand
it is him
preparing us right for what is coming
upon the earth.
>> So I think it's just you know just going
back to your what you just said Terry
it's God trains us. He allows us to see
things
um by faith
>> because he's trying to teach us how to
be prepared for what comes ahead.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen. I think it's uh it's the
first lady's t-shirt today, too. You
know, um God could easily I mean just
stop, right?
>> He could speak peace into any storm into
any of our lives at any moment, right?
Mhm.
>> It would be nothing for him to just say,
"Okay,
>> this bill's gone. This sickness is out
of the way. This annoyance, we're going
to move that out of the way over there."
I mean, he's able to part the Red Sea
still in our lives, but he doesn't.
>> And I think like with Moses, he says,
"What's that in your hand?" You know,
uh, we have it. And I I thank God for
the way he's been speaking to us. And
I'm I'm more and more every day keenly
aware that God in the process the
journey along the way he's accomplishing
something. Um a couple of months ago
maybe I think you know I've always
listened to uh the messages that you've
given pastor and uh even before I was
freed I was watching you and but I was
like a lot of people just taking it in.
You know we hear so much stuff and then
I think a few months ago the Lord said
Terry I want you to look at the process.
what's going on. It's the things you say
at the end of a message. You could have
said them at the beginning and we'd be
done.
>> But God saying, you know, watch the
process of how I'm unfolding this truth.
And at the same time, something is
happening inside of your heart and mine.
And the light is being uh you're being
anchored and you're being settled and
you're being grounded and you're being
rooted. And you may even see some things
that maybe the pastor didn't see, but
I'm saying something specifically for
your life. And I've been hearing more
and more of the saints saying that. So I
am thankful that God is he's leading
this church and he's doing something and
getting us ready for what's coming. So
you know my main thing I want to do when
I listen to uh our our believers and
listen to some of our prayer warriors
and and our meetings is try to encourage
people. Don't don't be discouraged
because of what you're going through.
>> It doesn't mean it's over because you're
going through a struggle or a trial.
God's getting you ready. Cooking
Mhm.
>> Amen.
>> He's in the kitchen cooking. He's about
to serve He's He's about to serve you a
meal.
A miracle.
>> Amen.
>> The miracle is the meal.
>> I'm just thinking about my let him cook
sermon.
>> I'm [laughter] thinking about my let him
cook,
>> you know. And it takes time for for
Yeah, it takes time. I mean, God and the
thing is it doesn't take God time to
work to work his miracle to answer our
prayers. It doesn't take him time. He's
God. But he purposely
takes time to slow cook a lot of our
miracles
>> just for us to strengthen our faith.
>> Simmer.
>> Yeah.
>> It's kind of like um your sermon um
>> Jael
>> where um the city of refuge.
>> The city of refuge.
>> So God is like
>> revenger of blood.
>> Revenger of blood. I just gave it a
whole new name, but those were points in
um but he is supernaturally
running slow
even though you know so to get you guys
got to hear the sermon. Have you
preached that here? You need to preach
that here.
>> I don't know if I've ever
>> I don't think you've ever preached it
here.
>> That's an oldie but goody guys. But that
but I mean he he could
>> he could have caught us but he's
supernaturally running slow to let us
get into
>> the city
>> of refuge to save us. Yeah.
>> To save us.
>> So, he's supernaturally slow cooking
your meal
>> so you can learn how to have to trust
him. Just to have real faith, to never
worry or stress, just the another
t-shirt I have, just immediately forward
it to God
>> and just give it to him.
>> Yep.
>> Hey Renee, I just saw your message. Uh,
reach out to Patrice at Livingmana
um.urch.
>> patrice livinga.urch.
>> Membership. Let's talk about uh your
daughter.
>> Okay. Yeah. Yay.
>> Um
>> Yeah. So,
>> livelive
living, but we'll be going over living
his email um during during the
announcements.
>> Yeah.
So, uh
>> Yeah. Yes. Sometimes we may be put in
the pressure cooker.
That's that's a true statement.
>> That's a true statement. Um,
>> God has different ways of cooking,
>> you know. Um,
so,
so, okay. So, I I think
>> I will say this.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> This kind of takes us back to what we
were saying um, months prior, weeks
prior about patience, about how all the
fruit of the spirit work together. Now
that I'm here walking in faith and I
know that God's building my faith, uh,
he's cooking and sometimes he wants to
slow cook and there's a good reason for
So, I'm going to need some patience.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. That other fruit work along with
this. I've got to be able to have faith
and patience. As a matter of fact, in
Hebrews chapter 6, it said that through
faith and patience, we inherit the
promises with Abraham.
>> Praise God.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. Regina say, "Praise God, Regina,
>> I see your your request as well. Please
do the same. Reach out to to to Patrice.
>> It's Patrice living.live
and I will go over that information
again right during the welcome for the
divine worship service." Yeah.
>> So, praise God.
>> Amen. Amen. Um,
it is
it is there's a there was a a um
and I think I've shared this before as
well,
>> but uh there was a really really popular
uh movie way back in the day. Way back
in the day. um
that
the in the beginning scene
um
I'll just say the name Leroy is blind is
uh blindfolded [laughter]
and the master is [snorts] shooting
arrows at him and the arrows are colored
and
I see you nodding your head Terry. Uh,
>> yeah,
>> he he's
>> Is that Bruce Leroy or no? What's it
called?
>> He's I'm just Okay, just Leroy. Okay,
>> I'm just I'm just leaving it at
>> I've really never seen that.
>> And he's breaking the arrows. This is
the very beginning of the movie. He's
breaking the arrows and you know the
master is shooting these arrows at him.
He's breaking the arrows and then
master shoots uh blue arrow and he
catches the arrow.
>> Yeah. And then the master stops and he
pulls off his his blindfold and he's
like, "How did you know that was the
one?" And he's like, "I don't know. I"
And he was like, "How did you know?" And
he was like, "I don't know." And then
he's like, "Your training is over." And
he's like, "But master, your training is
over." And now he has And that's how the
thing begins, right? And I've always
remember that scene because especially
now
faith is that how did you know?
How did you know? Right? I see y'all in
the comments. How did you know? That's
what faith is. Faith is knowing without
knowing.
>> It is it is the inability to explain.
How did you know to trust God in this
situation? How did you know? I I don't
know. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> And that
>> it's amazing how many people in the
comments know the movie. [laughter]
>> I see them. Yeah, we're dating
ourselves, too. Um, [laughter] but that
ability to to uh,
you know, and it's so funny, Terry,
because
>> what it is is
the spirit
is giving us to give us that glow.
>> Amen.
>> Wow.
>> To give us that glow. And when you have
that glow,
when you got that glow,
when you have the
>> Isn't it amazing?
>> It It's kind of amazing how much the
world Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. They take all of our stuff.
>> Yep.
>> Because I'm thinking Isaiah 61 that that
glow that glory that's ours.
>> Yes.
Yes.
And so, so when you say how do you know,
right?
>> Um, you know, I got to think about in
the world, there's so many reasons, you
know, and rationale and, you know,
logical reasons to come up to come to
certain conclusions about what's going
on in the world and what's happening in
the world and we don't want to get
caught up in that spirit that you you're
talking about last night. How do we just
know that we know that we know, right? M
>> that's what that's what I want and I
know that's what our living mana family
wants. You hear it all the time from
them. We want to know you, Lord,
>> and hear your voice.
>> Y
>> we want to
and and while the whole world's going
this way, we may be looking crazy going
that way, but that's the way we're
going, you know. And uh pray that
everybody will see our glow and and and
and follow.
>> Yep.
>> Amen.
>> Um all right.
How much time do we have?
>> We um I'm the time keeper, but we have
about 15 more minutes.
>> Okay.
>> About really like 20 minutes to meet.
Really?
>> Yeah.
>> 21 minutes.
>> I don't know if it's wise for us to move
on to the next uh segment. Um which is
>> the survival of the meas.
>> We'll just just start it. We'll just
start it.
>> Okay. Um, let me I'll say this uh in
closing on on the whole faith thing here
and bl being blindfolded is
it is when we're blindfolded that we can
see what God sees.
So,
>> there's an interesting dynamic in the in
the Garden of Eden where
when Adam and Eve eat from the tree,
their eyes are open,
which is it's just a really
>> weird thing because wait a minute, how
uh
how did
how Did how were they able to see
[clears throat]
>> when to see the tree to eat from the
tree of the knowledge of good and evil?
What do you mean their eyes were open?
Um
their spiritual eyes had already been
open,
>> right? And then when they ate
then their eyes were open in a new way.
Their carnal eyes. Yes. Their carnal
eyes
>> were open.
>> Were open.
And so
I think the parallel there is carnal
eyes.
Um
when your carnal eyes are open, you
can't see the spiritual. Mhm.
>> When your spiritual eyes are open, you
don't see the carnal.
>> So, we're we're either blind to one or
the other,
>> right?
We're either blind. [cough]
We are either blind to the to the faith
world or we're blind to this world. So
remember Elijah's servant right as um
they are surrounded and he prays Lord
open the eyes of my servant that he may
see and when his eyes were open they
were surrounded with chariots of fire.
>> Um that is
what it means
right to see the invisible and that's
what faith is. Faith is seeing the
>> Amen. That's what faith is.
>> Yeah. What you just said kind of reminds
me of what uh Paul said in 1 Corinthians
14. He says uh brethren,
be not children in understanding, how be
it in malice
>> be children.
>> Right? But in understanding be men. And
it just what you said is like Lord, we
would want to get back to our innocence
and docility of a child. We want to get
back to that.
>> Yeah. Right. But it seems that now sin
has opened our eyes up into such a new
way that we're constantly fighting these
thoughts of malice, these thoughts of
independence, these thoughts of
self-sufficiency, these thoughts of
pride, these thoughts, you know, the the
challenge to try to do it our way
instead of always being 100% dependent
upon God moment by moment.
>> Well, I want to be converted and become
a child again. And I love what Sister
White said about that. Even when we come
to the word of God, we've got to come
with the docsility and the humility of a
child. And if we don't, then what will
happen? Those e evil angels will corrupt
our mind so bad.
>> You know that we won't even be impressed
by the truth.
>> Yep.
>> Yep. I like what blessing Joy just said.
So faith is being able to see behind the
veil,
>> which is exactly what we preached about.
What was it preached about last week or
the week before? Um the invisible, the
hidden kingdom.
>> The hidden kingdom.
>> Um
>> yeah. Is there any any parallel with
Revelation 17 about being blind? Uh
yeah, I think so because I think
Revelation se 3:17, you're miserable,
wretched, naked, and blind is
basically saying, listen, you're you're
blind
to the spiritual realm. You're blind to
the things of the spirit
>> because your eyes are open to the things
of this world.
>> So it's kind of like Jesus said, you
know, if you are blind
um how did he say if you were blind then
you're s you know man it's slipping my
mind now. You know what I'm talking
about Terry. If you were blind
>> Yes. John chapter nine.
>> Yeah. Then uh let me get to the last
part where he says because you say you
see your blindness remains
>> is basically what he's saying.
>> Right.
>> So
>> exactly
>> it is it is interesting how when we if
we confess and admit blindness
>> that is a first step to seeing.
>> Amen.
>> But when we say we see
>> that's John 9:41. He said that.
>> Yeah. When we say we see, our sin
remains, our blindness remains.
>> So Lord, put on me the divine blindfold.
Someone said it earlier,
>> right?
>> Put on me the divine blindfold and teach
me how
>> to actually walk by faith.
>> Yeah. The blindfold makes you have
faith.
>> Without the blindfold, you're your your
works. It's your own works. You're not
trusting in God.
>> Yeah. And who wants to walk around with
a blindfold? We all want to.
>> We all want to see,
>> but then we're guiding, but when we see
when we see I'm sorry, Terry, but when
we see, we're guiding our we're guiding
our steps.
>> The blindfold makes us follow God's
steps, which makes us in his will.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> You know what's interesting? Um, I know
we were going to look at the make it,
but we probably won't look at me. Uh,
Yeah. So, I was looking at this in
Exodus that um when he when Pharaoh told
the Hebrew wives that if the Hebrew
women had a baby and it was a male to
destroy it, if it was a female to allow
it to live. And those
Hebrew midwives name was Shiffra and
Pua. Interesting. The male babies were
the ones who grew up to fill Israel's
ranks of their army. fill the fill the
army's ranks, right? They were fighters.
>> And it's interesting that shipra and pua
means brightness and glitter.
>> Sort of like the the the things of this
world, the the brightness and the
glitter, the things that cause us
warriors to become entangled and
distract from the spiritual world, but
the things the enemies are trying the
enemy is trying to use, you know, to
blind our eyes to what God is actually
wanting us to focus on. And and I think
everybody I know me and anybody watching
know that there's something inside of us
that we always have to stay on top of.
We have to always be up under
>> uh uh as Paul said, under our bodies and
keep it in subjection because the things
of this world are designed to allure us
and entice us.
>> Those shiny things, those bright,
glittery, flashy things, you know, those
are the things that uh can can destroy
the warrior spirit, I believe.
>> Yep.
>> Amen. Um I I just had a thought too that
uh Oh man.
Uh yes
yes yes.
[clears throat]
I think that the example
and this is so so you know so remember
when they blindfolded Jesus
>> and they're hitting him right
>> and they're like who hit you
>> and hit you
>> just what a thought what a thought that
he's like wait do y'all think that I
don't know who hit me just now
[laughter]
>> do you think this blindfold is like
blinding me.
He knew exactly right.
>> He wasn't like, "I don't know who hit
me."
>> When they he could have he could have
terrified these guys to death and shown
that he was God by simply saying, "All
right, the one who hit me just now, your
name is, and the one who hit me just
now, your name is." Can you imagine how
they would have been like
>> like, "Uh, yeah."
>> But he doesn't do that, right?
>> He doesn't do that. And but I think the
the the lesson for us there
>> is that
in wearing the blindfold of God
>> he allows us to see things
>> that we normally wouldn't see.
>> Amen.
>> You know, in allowing ourselves to be
blindfolded,
>> he will allow us to see things that we
typically
wouldn't see. Mhm.
>> Um,
>> wow.
>> And the just
live by that, right?
>> So, the just h
>> are blindfolded,
>> but they have a better understanding of
what's going on,
>> right,
>> than those
who see.
>> Yeah.
>> Pastor, you just uh
>> I'm I'm sorry. We keep I'm sorry
[laughter] for
>> No, go ahead. Go ahead.
>> You just led right into your next
because I was I was looking over your
note last night and you said that the
warrior who uh the Christian warrior has
nothing to boast about. And you know
Jesus could have easily said, "Okay,
look. I know who hit me. It was you. It
was you. I know where you're from. I
know your age. I know everything about
you. I know your security is. I know I
know where I know where your mama lives.
I'm just kidding. [laughter]
>> He could have said anything crazy, but
he wouldn't say that.
>> And And so, you know, that just led
right into what you were talking about
with meekness. Sometimes we don't always
have to tell everything we know. We
don't always have to show and announce
everything we think, you know, we've
done or, you know, we don't have to
boast because we actually have nothing
to boast about.
>> Yeah.
>> He knew who he was. He knew his purpose.
Look, I don't have to give nobody a
piece of my mind every time. You know,
they say something sideways to me.
Sometimes we just hold our peace.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. See, not that we're going to get
into meekness because we're definitely
not getting into, [laughter]
>> but I you know, I I often think about
just imagine, you know, you are you are
the guys that put Jesus on the cross.
that are called for his death and then
you hear that he is alive.
>> Oh wow. Yeah.
>> And just imagine what you're thinking
like
am I going to wake up in the middle of
the night and find Jesus
>> by my like is he coming to get me?
>> And Jesus could have done that.
>> You know what I'm saying? Jesus could
have been like, "All right, and now it's
my turn."
>> Hey,
Caiaphas,
wake up.
>> Imagine the terror and the fear that
they must have have been living with,
>> wondering if this man who was raised
from the dead is going to come and seek
vengeance.
>> Amen.
What an example of
>> the spirit of meekness.
>> Amen.
>> Wow. That's beautiful because I I know
all of us can think of a time when
someone probably expected us to
>> exact vengeance or go off with harsh
words or they knew they had it coming
and we decided, "No, I'm going to show
you the humility of Christ, the love of
Jesus instead."
>> Yep. and uh show the love of God. That's
powerful.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. Amen.
Well, this is since we're not going to
go into survival of Mikas, we'll pick up
with that next week, unless
>> something happens and we do like a
another impromptu Sabbath school. But if
not, we are definitely going to pick up
with the survival of Mikas next week.
Please, I mean, thank you for going
through this study with us today. Um, if
you have not gotten the book or the um
the four chapters that are in Mighty
Networks, please sign up. If you don't
know how to sign up for Mighty Networks,
it's going to be in the chat. Uh, we can
put in the chat now, but we're also
going to put it in the chat at the
beginning of the divine worship service
so that you can uh download the copies
of the chapters of the book um so that
you can be studying along with us. We
want you to be this is a Sabbath school
study that we are doing together. So we
want you to definitely be a part of it.
And do you want to share some about your
sermon?
>> So the sermon uh is entitled the house
of David. And uh it is um you know what
do I what do I keep saying? I kind of,
you know, I often just like it's not
what you think and I
>> is it don't want to give any spoiler
alerts.
>> So, it's just hard to explain. Just, you
know, just think that that title right
there, the house of David
>> just means
everything.
We're just gonna we're just going to
unpack that title right there in the
context of the verse I will be sharing
>> about this title about this this name
that that this this title the house of
David [clears throat]
and um
um it will speak to you in a very
personal and encouraging way. So if you
need encouragement today,
>> if you're struggling with an issue in
your life,
>> this sermon today is it.
>> So this is for everyone that is in the
hearing of my voice because we are all
going through something. We live in this
world, right? We're all struggling with
something. This is for everyone. So
please uh subscribe, like, and share.
That's what we'd like for you to do
between uh now and the divine worship
service.
>> Subscribe to this channel. Like that.
Helps it to push it out into
>> the living mana online channel. Living
mana online YouTube channel.
>> Yes. This helps to push it out into uh
the the the uh online world uh so people
can can see uh who we are and what we're
doing. And then for a friend, a family
member, um send this link, invite them
to church. And also, yeah, so just like,
subscribe, and share this link because
everyone, what he just shared, everyone
needs to hear what we're all about to
hear. Uh because we are all going
through something and struggling with
something. We live in this very
>> uh wicked, sinful world that is uh just
not our friend.
Um, and because of, you know, we have an
enemy that does not uh want good for us.
So, we all need to hear this sermon.
Whoever you share this with will be
blessed.
>> And yeah. Oh, also want to say, please,
Brother Terry and and um I'm not sure if
there's an extra team and Amber will be
praying over your prayer request. Um, so
please put your prayer request in the
chat. I know some of you who already
know the drill have been doing that from
the time we went live, but uh it's not
too late. Please put your prayer request
in the chat as well.
>> Amen.
>> So,
>> all right, let's close in prayer.
>> Yes.
>> And uh then we'll see you in the divine
service. Let's pray. Heavenly Father,
thank you, Lord, for um the word you
gave us today, Lord, in our Sabbath
school. We continue to pray, Lord, that
you would make us faith fighters, Lord.
that you would help us to be blind to
this world and yet uh um
>> keen in eyesight to the things of the
spirit, Lord.
>> So teach us to to uh to to walk by
faith, not by sight. Help us, Lord, to
hear the wind when it blows and to move
with it, Lord. And um we just thank you,
Lord, for your love for us. Uh continue
to bless us as we worship you, Lord.
Bless his service, we pray. Bless all
who have who are listening and will
watch uh in the future. Lord, please
just uh grant them a portion of your
spirit. We thank you and we love you. In
Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
Who get
>> better to stay here for 100 more if
that's what it takes to protect mom and
jail. And if not enough, we'll stay here
for 100 more. If that's not enough,
we'll stay here for 100 more.
>> I'm not Hawaiian by blood, but I'm
Hawaiian by heart. My grandmother was
born on Maui, daughter of a plantation
worker. I was born and raised in Wua in
Nanukuli on Aahu. This is the only home
I know, and I'm blessed to be Kei Oka, a
child of this land. My wife and I were
in Russia when we saw the videos of the
stand here on Mount Aaya. We were
speaking each night to over a thousand
Russian young people at a spiritual
youth congress under the theme striving
for the highest. And though we were
there on the other side of this world,
our hearts and our prayers were here
with the people on this mountain. When
we flew back home, we came immediately
here to listen, to learn, to absorb, and
to stand. The kapuna tell us kya ikanuku
which means aim for the highest and
strive for the summit. And that's what
we've done here today. You see mount aa
is the highest mountain in [music] the
world from the ocean floor. It is the
peak and the pinnacle of havi. We stand
on this mountain today in capu aloha
holding ourselves up to the highest
standards of aloha at pono. And as we
have physically ascended the mounta we
are called to rise mentally and
spiritually as well. But today our
hearts are heavy because we see our aa
trampled upon by greed and lust and
vanity. Our hearts are sore because
we've seen the aloha spirit
commercialized for profit by those who
know not what it is. But though our
hearts are heavy, we like this ma must
rise above it.
When the fierce and strong hurricane
clashes with the ma, it remains on paha
steadfast. The ma overcomes the storm.
And in the same way as a people, we face
a fierce storm today. A storm of
oppression that has brought disease, a
drug epidemic, homelessness, pollution,
and brokenness in our beloved land. And
as we've seen and experienced oppression
and injustice, our human nature wants to
respond in the same way. To respond in
anger and vengeance and even war. But
today, a coup is calling us to kala
ikanu to strive for the summit. to go
higher in our thinking and our actions
and our reactions. And this, my friends,
is the call of Kaku aloha.
But please consider with me that before
we can go as high as this mountain, we
must first go deep like the ocean. The
mountain is the tallest in the world
because it finds its foundation deep on
the ocean floor. And this is a life
lesson for us. In order for us to reach
to the highest heavens, we must first go
to the deepest ocean. You can only go
high as you first go deep. You see,
every tree has branches and it's the
branches that hold the fruit of the
tree. But the branches are only as
strong as the roots. In order to [music]
have sweet fruits, you first must have
healthy roots. You see what the aa is
teaching us is that in order for us to
only to stand tall and steadfast, we
must first go deep to the roots. My
generation are the branches and the
fruit of our kapuna. We are the answer
to their pulle, their prayers. But they
are our roots. We must remember those
who came before us and never [music]
forget the lessons of our elders and our
history. But please consider with me
that Aku is calling us to go even deeper
than that. For you can only go as high
as you first go deep. So the deeper you
go, the higher you will go as well. So
in order to [music] kya ekan to reach
for the summit of this mountaintop
experience, we must go far deeper than
the land that our feet [music] walks
upon. And we must reach back even
further before our capuna and before
their capuna. We must go back [music] to
the beginning of time to find the truest
and the purest form of capu aloha. And
where is that you ask? In the beginning,
Akua created the heavens and the earth.
And Akua said, "Let there be light." And
there [music] was light. You see friends
before our kapuna and even before our
aina there was only aka. The Bible says
that Aka made the aa first then he made
mankind [music] after then he gave the
aina to the first kanaka ma the original
man. The Bible says that Aka gave the aa
to us to have dominion over. The Bible
is clear that the kanaka are the
guardians of this land. But the land can
only [music] be perpetuated in
righteousness. And tragically, there
have been many who have misunderstood
and misinterpreted this biblical truth.
Some missionaries of the past and clergy
of the present have used this to justify
the taking, the exploiting, and the
destroying of the But in Genesis chapter
2, Aku tells us how we're to have
[music] dominion over the Aina. It says
that we're to dress it and to keep it.
In other words, we're to be stewards of
the land, servants of Aka, called to
Malama, the aa. This is the true origin
of aloha aa. We exercise dominion over
the aina. Not by exploitation but by
aloha. This is what I call servant
leadership. We lead and we rule. We
dominate and we conquer. Not by the
power of force but by our service and
our aloha to the land and our service
and aloha to one another. By continuing
to [music] do what we're doing here
today in capu aloha. to hold ourselves
up to the highest standards of pono and
aloha to respond to those who desecrate
our aa with the highest level of
nonviolent resistance respect compassion
empathy patience strength and love to
show the whole world that the mana of
aloha conquers all so I call upon you
today my beloved lahi in the name of a
to remain on pa in the mana of kapu
aloha one last thing I'm compelled to
share with you is
There is another ma that is even higher
than this one. A mountain that is
[music] demonstrated most clearly to us.
The mana of Capu aloha. It is a mountain
that our capuna [music] and many of our
beloved kings and queens of Havi looked
toward for strength to endure the storms
they faced. It is the mountain called
Calvary. For it is there that Akua sent
his beloved son Yesu to die in the cross
for each one of us. And on that sacred
mountain by the mana of Capu [music]
aloha Yesu conquered all the forces of
oppression, injustice, hatred and
violence. He laid down his life in order
to free us from the oppression [music]
of sin. He laid down his life to provide
for us here today the mana to remain
onipa in capu aloha. The power to remain
steadfast in love to love those who
disrespect us. to pull those who would
oppress us, to bless those who would
harm us, to resist those [music] who
would trample upon us, to forgive those
who would take advantage of us.
So let us go up to the mountain, not
only physically, but mentally and
spiritually. Let us reach [music] back
even further and go even deeper so that
we can rise even higher. Let us kala to
strive for the summit. I appeal to you
my beloved lahi and all of those who
face difficulties and oppression around
the world. In the name of Akua to focus
and look even higher than the aa that we
can see with our physical eye with the
eye of faith. [music] Let us look beyond
the furthest star and the most distant
galaxy that any man-made telescope can
penetrate. Let us look to [music] the
return of a Yesu in the clouds of
heaven. Soon he will return to take us
to our heavenly aua, a land that no
[music] one will be able to take from
us. Let us look up towards this mountain
here today. But let us also look even
higher to the mountain of Calvary where
we obtain the mana of Capu aloha. And
then let us look again even higher yet
to our heavenly Holly, our heavenly Au
pua of which our beloved Havi is a
reflection of. For there in that
beautiful lamb, we will never be
oppressed again. Injustice will [music]
end. Sickness will be no more. Death
itself will die. Our tears will dry up.
Laughter will never cease [music] and
joy will never dim. Our capuna will
never age and our kei will never die.
The sky will never darken. [music] And
the flowers will never fade. Our waters
will always be clean and our land will
always be beautiful and our ma will
continue to stand. Aloha. Aloha kakua.
Aloha kako. I'll see you in that
heavenly ma.
All
[music]
[singing]
I'm [singing]
[music]
[singing]
We are [music and singing] all
[music]
>> [singing]
>> kind
[music]
[music and singing]
of
spe Heat. Heat.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat. [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[music]
Heat. Heat. [music]
Heat. Heat.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat.
[music]
Heat.
Heat
up
here.
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat.
[music]
>> Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
We're so happy that you decided to
continue to worship with us today. If
you are just joining us for the first
time today, please put in the chat where
you are viewing from. And if you were
with us during our first uh program, but
you didn't put in the chat where you're
viewing from. Please let us know where
you're viewing from. And if this is your
very first time worshiping with Living
Mana Church, please put a one in the
chat. We want to tell you all about
Living Mata Church, who we are, uh, and
invite you to some of our other programs
that we do during the week, and we just
want to tell you a little bit more about
us. So, please put in the chat at this
time where you are viewing from. It was
such a blessing to do Sabbath school. It
was a smaller uh panel just the pastor
and myself and brother Terry but it was
a blessing to share just about how God
wants to build our faith by he wants us
to be spiritually blindfolded. He wants
us to just let him do his work and not
bother him or don't worry or don't have
anxiety. He wants us to just let him do
the work while he's working on the
miracle that he is working on for each
and every one of us for the situations
that we are going through. But I'd like
to uh say a welcome to we have uh uh
let's see Rose in New York. Oh, and this
is your first time. Welcome Rose to
Living uh Mana Church. So good to see
you and to have you here with us. Uh we
are a completely online church and we
are not just here on Sabbath. We have
programs all throughout the week. I'm
going to talk about some of those
programs here shortly, but we have
mental health uh programming on Monday.
We have physical health on Tuesday. We
have two prayer services on Wednesday.
And we have many small groups. And so,
we just want to I will be I will share
more with you in just a moment here as
we uh continue to go through this.
Welcome. But you will get to hear about
everything that Living Mana Church is
doing and hopefully you will find
something that is just for you. Um and
you will get involved in that. Want to
say welcome because a lot of you are
putting in the in the chat want to say a
special welcome. We have somebody
watching from let me go up a little
further. Of course we have let's see
here. We have someone watching from
Lach, Texas. So, welcome to Living Mana
Church, Spring Hill, Tennessee, welcome.
We have South Carolina, welcome. Glad to
have you here. We have St. St. Martin.
Uh, Dutch Caribbean, welcome to Living
Mana Church. We have Tanzania. Always
good to see um our family and friends
there in Tanzania worshiping with us.
Welcome to Living Mana Church. Um, also,
um, we have East East Europe, Serbia.
Welcome again. Don't sure if that's the
same person or if that's another one,
but welcome from from Serbia. Good to
see you there. We have Barbara from
Anguila. Always great to see you here at
Living Mana Church. And let's see, I
don't think Oh, I did miss a few here.
There's Indianapolis. Welcome our sister
there. Always good to see you. Good to
have you here as always. And um yeah, so
continue to put in the in the chat where
you're viewing from. We love to see it.
We love that we have viewer all around
the world. We have membership all around
the world. And it is just amazing to see
everyone and to see how this message is
going all around the world. And we have
family um like I call you guys family
because you are our church family and
you're all around the world and you are
a blessing to uh this church. We have
Orlando, Florida here as well. also
Connecticut. So we have many around the
United States and it's a blessing to
have all of you. Want to let you guys
know how you can stay connected to
Living Man Church, how we can stay
connected to you as well. If you are
here in North America, you can sign up
to get text alerts and you will be able
to to do that by um texting LMOC to that
855 number that you see on your screen.
You can also scan the QR code and that
will automatically sign you up to get
these text alerts. It's wonderful
because when you're just busy throughout
the week and you'll get like a text
alert that says, "Hey, Living Man is
going live for their mental health
Monday or true health Tuesday or their
prayer service or the sermon for Sabbath
is going live in 20 minutes." it will
give you uh 20 about 20 minutes to get
prepared or to remember that that is
that that program is is going live and
so it's great for our busy busy
lifestyles but that is only if you are
here in North America will this uh text
service work for you as you know I just
said we're an international church so if
you are not in North America you will
have to sign up for Mighty Networks and
honestly as I always say everyone needs
to sign up for Mighty Networks because
there's so much on mighty networks. It
is our virtual church home. So you will
not only just get text alerts if you are
on mighty networks and you are
international around the world, but you
will also find the small groups that you
might want to get involved with. You can
meet other church members and viewing
audience. And that is this is where we
build our community. There's so much on
mighty networks. This is where you can
download pastor's um book, The Christian
Art of War. Um you can by chapter by
chapter is on mighty networks. And so
there's so many and there's many many
other things on mighty networks that you
really need to sign up to find out what
is all there um to be a part of living
mana church. It just keeps you connected
and informed and you get to again build
community with us if you are on mighty
networks. And there is going to be a
link in the chat so that you can sign up
for Mighty Networks if you have not
already done so. So this is that's this
is our virtual community um home, our
church home. And so we want you guys to
be a part of that. Also want to remind
you that we do have children's
programming with LMOC Kids. And if you
want your child to get involved with
LMOC kids, you can text kids to that 855
number or you can email the leadership
uh with that email that you see on the
screen. And these kids are learning
powerful things just like you're
learning um during the Sabbath school
time here with Living Man Church. As
adults, they are learning power powerful
things um on the children's level for
children as well. And so they are having
lots of fun doing it. There's music,
there's games, there arts and crafts,
and they are just going deep into God's
word. So if you want to get your child,
if there's someone you know that wants
to get their child involved, you can
text kids to that 855 number or send an
email to the leadership team so you can
get your child uh involved in LOCC kids.
Also, Pastor Meyers does have virtual
church office hours. And if you would
like to meet with Pastor Meyers, please
schedule an appointment by sending an
email to patrice@ livingmana.live
and she will get that set up for you.
Also, there were a lot of uh people
wanting to know about membership uh in
the comments in the chat today during
our first service. So, I want to let you
guys know how you can do that. to become
a member of Living Mana Church. There's
three different ways you can do that.
You can, if you are a member of the
Seventh Day Adventist Church already and
your membership is at another church,
you can have your membership transferred
to LivingMana Church and that you would
be sending an email to Patrice at
Livingmana.live.
If you have been baptized and into
another church and you've been baptized
before and you want to join Living Mana
Church but don't feel like you need to
get rebaptized, you can join by
profession of faith. Uh and that's the
way you could become a member of Living
Mana Church. And again, the email to do
that is patrice livinga.live.
And if you want to get baptized um and
into and you want to get baptized in the
7th day avenist church and become a
member of living matter church, you can
get baptized. And the way to do that
again is sending an email to patrice
livingmana.live and pastor meers will
baptize you. So those are the three ways
that you can become a member of living
mana church. So those who are inquiring
about that during our Sabbath school
time, please send an email to patrice
livinga.live and uh she will get things
started for you.
Also want to just remind you um I was
going to remind you. Yes, we do have the
power line. We have the power line
that's on Wednesdays at 8:00 PM Central
time. And the power line is live prayer.
We're praying over prayer request live.
And so you bring your prayer request and
the team that is doing the power line
for that day is going to pray over your
request. You can tell pe you can tell
your family members. You can tell people
at work, your friends, whoever you meet,
strangers on the street. If they say,
"Hey, would you like for me to pray for
you?" You can pray for them right there.
You can say, "Hey, I'm going to have my
church pray for you." You can bring
their prayer request to the power line
and we will pray. And you can invite
them to even watch and participate um in
the pro. All they're doing if they want
to participate is just viewing and
hearing somebody else pray for them. So
that that's what the power line is. and
uh they uh meet at 8:00 p.m. Central
time um every Wednesday uh again at 8:00
p.m. Just wanted to remind you guys and
there may not be a slide for this and
that's okay that mental health Monday
will not be this Monday as we'll be
observing uh the Martin Luther King
holiday but will return the following
Monday. Also wanted to uh remind you
guys that true health Tuesday uh with
Dr. Maria Humel is such a blessing and
you want to tune in to that if you want
to. She's a licensed she's a doctor and
she's a licensed uh nutritionist and she
is telling us the things that we can eat
that can help us to to either maintain
our health or help to build our health
and it's so very important the
information she is sharing it's for free
guys and you would all you would
honestly think you would have to pay
somebody to get this information. So
definitely tune in to True Health
Tuesdays. Want to tell you guys about
the digital small groups. Um the digital
small groups or let's see the or we can
talk about the adult Sabbath school.
Let's talk about that. Um if you're
looking for a place to grow deeper in
God's word and connect with your church
family, join us Friday night at 6:30
p.m. for Adult Sabbath School hosted by
GEMS. together. We'll uh dive into the
Sabbath school quarterlys and share
insights, ask questions, and encourage
one another in faith. This isn't just
study. It's fellowship, reflection, and
and character building time. Um and that
that carries you through the week. Come
ready to be inspired, challenged, and
uplifted. text gems to that 855 number
that you see on the screen if you would
like to get involved.
And I want to share with you guys about
the digital small groups that you can
get uh involved in. We excited to share
that sister Angela has stepped up to the
role of department head for the personal
ministries department. Under her
leadership, we look forward to seeing
all the digital small groups continue to
flourish. um as a as um spaces for
prayer, study and accountability and
connection. Digital small groups are
more than meetings. They are communities
where faith becomes practical.
Friendships grow and lives are transfer
transformed, excuse me. Uh whether you
are seeking support, deeper Bible study,
or a place to share your favorite hobby,
there's a group for you. So just check
out the small groups, see which one you
are interested in. And again, you can do
that on mighty networks. Want to share
with you a small group that has uh been
going on and it's amazing group and it's
called Star Steps to Addiction Recovery.
Um this Sabbath we're highlighting our
digital small group STAR hosted by Ross
and Gina Brower. Um, it's a Christ
centered space for anyone seeking
freedom and support on the journey of
recovery. If you or someone you love is
looking uh for encouragement, prayer,
and practical steps toward healing, star
is here. It is it's it's the
it is just a step closer to you healing
and being and and your recovery. So, we
definitely want if you're interested in
that, definitely uh text star to that
number. Looking forward for those who
getting involved in that. Also want you
to uh know about the glow small group,
the glow groups.
Um it's carrying it's carrying the word
all week. Another amazing ministry to
come out of the personal ministries
department as our glow groups which are
uh designed to take pastor meers Sabbath
sermons beyond the service um and into
your daily walk. Each week these groups
dive deeper into pastor's sermon through
study uh targeted prayers, journaling
and character building activities. It's
a to it's a way to let the word shape
not just you not just to shape you on
Sabbath but your entire week. If you
feel called to help others grow in
Christ, consider becoming a glow group
host. For more information, please reach
out uh to groups at living.urch.
Together we can keep the light of God's
word glowing in our lives every day. So
that's exciting uh to be able to reflect
and continue to go deeper into uh the
word together that is shared on Sabbath.
So also want you to know about Friday
night lights. That's the LC teens. We
don't leave the teens out on Friday
nights. Under new leadership, LMLC teens
is stepping into a whole new season of
energy, creativity, and community. Teens
now have their own dedicated space where
they're not just attending. They are
leading, building, and shaping the
movement. Friday Night Lights is more
than a Bible study. It's a teenun um
teenled experience where young people
dive deep into God's word and grow
spiritually and discover how to use
their gifts for his glory. all while all
while building real friendships that
last. And so this is exciting. So if you
have a if you have a teen or know a teen
ages 13 through 18, this is a community
just for them. And if you want more
information, you can email them lmlc
teens living.urch.
So, we are excited for uh the new um
it's not new. We've had it, but the new
leadership over uh the teens uh
ministry. It's very exciting. Want you
guys to know and to remind you about
LMLC global. It's just like what it
sounds like. It is Living Mana going
global. We do go global, but we want to
go in the languages of the world. And
so, right now, we're going in seven
different languages. We've had some
videos really um really I don't want to
say go went go viral but we've they've
had a lot of views and have gone around
uh the world in those languages. So we
want to continue to support Alamosci
Global and we want you to have um just
see a little snippet of what that looks
like um at this time.
Dochech.
[music]
Fore!
Wow!
Fore
[music]
able to go all around the world and be
an international church, but it's even
more amazing to be able to go around the
world in the languages of the world. And
so, if you want to continue to support
uh living mana global, then I want to
let you know how you can do that. You
can uh continue to give through
adventistgiving.org.
Here you put in living mana church and
you will see a virtual tithe envelope uh
dropdown if you click in the righth hand
corner and there you can give your tithe
which goes to the northeastern
conference which living mana church is
uh a church that is a member of that
conference and then you can see where it
says local church local church when you
give to that section is what stays with
us and we are able to continue to do all
the things that we need to do to support
the church and to uh be able to go live
with all of the equipment um and
everything that this church does. So
everything that uh we do here at Living
Manage Church comes from that local uh
church budget and then you'll see
different line items. There's a
benevolence fund where we are able to
help those who are in need. When you
give to that, we're able to take it from
that area and you will see many other
areas that you can give and support. So,
if um giving online is not what you
would like to do, if you would like to
uh mail in your tithe or offering, you
can do that as well. You can um just
send us uh a check and to PO Box 428,
Owens Crossroads, Alabama 35763.
And when you mail it in, please put a
note in the envelope that says if it's
for tithe, for offering, if it's
benevolence fund, or for another area
that you see on the tithe envelope that
you would like to support. So those are
the ways that you can continue or start
financially supporting uh living mana
church. And it is just such a blessing
because here we are entering into almost
our fourth year of existence. on April
9th. It will be four years and we are
just so thankful uh to God uh for what
he has done for living mana church and
bringing us to this point. It is truly a
blessing. All of you have financially
supported. You've supported through uh
just showing up each and every week.
you've showed up for us through prayer
um and just being a loving community
that supports each other and a and a
community where we can invite others to
church and it's a safe space for them to
for them to come and learn about God um
and just to grow closer together to with
other um fellow Christians um who
believe like them or just help us to
foster new baby Christians um in this
faith as well. And so I just want to say
a huge thank you for all that you do for
Living Matt Church. We just want to put
send up a prayer of praise and
thanksgiving to God at this time. So if
you would please bow your heads with me
as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, thank you Lord
for the Sabbath, the rest, the
fellowship with other uh just family and
friends and members. It's just such a
blessing to come together and worship
with everyone that is viewing from all
around the world. Living Mana Church
truly is a blessing. It's been a
blessing to me personally for almost
four years. And we pray that this church
will continue to be a blessing to so
many others. Lord, we are just starting
a new year. And Lord, we depend upon you
to to lead this church and to guide this
church and to teach us and to show us
how we can continue uh to just go into
all the world and just share your gospel
to as many people as possible, Lord. And
Lord, I know that there's so many today
that are here in church. They've showed
up. They're faithful. They just showed
up to worship you, Lord. But everything
is not perfect in their life. And so, I
pray uh for those situations, Lord. I
pray for the marriages. I pray for the
parents. I pray for the children, the
grandchildren, Lord. You know, the
situations that are going on in
everyone's life, Lord. And I just pray
that you will work a miracle in those
situations. Lord, there's um those here
dealing with health issues. I pray that
you will heal them. I pray that you will
give them peace as they are going
through this struggle um as they are not
feeling well. Lord, I pray for the
family members that are supporting them
that you will strengthen them and give
them peace as they are being that
support system for their family member.
Lord, I just want to pray over the
financial uh issues that people are
going through, Lord. Nothing is too hard
for you, Lord. Providing enough money,
feeding, housing, none of that is too
hard for you, Lord. And so those who are
going through those struggles, I pray
that you will intervene um in their
situation, Lord, and you will provide
what they are needing. Lord, I want to
lift up Pastor Meyers and the sermon
today, the House of David. Lord, I pray
that you will help us all to be blessed
by this message. Help us help it to
touch our hearts the way that you want
it to. Lord, we ask all these things in
Jesus precious name. Amen.
Let's begin this [music] year with a
simple prayer. Not for more things, but
for more of him.
Not for ease,
but for his presence.
[music] Not for our will, but for his.
Lord, teach us to number our [music]
days
that we may gain a heart of wisdom.
Lead us in paths of righteousness
for your name's sake.
Give us ears [music] that hear your
voice.
Give us hands ready to serve with joy.
[music] Give us hearts that love as you
love.
Let this year be marked by surrender,
not striving.
by obedience,
not hesitation.
By prayer,
not pride.
And when the year is done, may we look
back and see your hand in every detail.
For yours is the [music] kingdom,
the power,
and the glory forever.
Amen.
to my heart
sing.
All
teach
[screaming]
might
Yeah.
Are you done?
>> [music]
>> Hey,
hey,
hey.
>> [music]
>> Jesus
[screaming]
I
hope
save me You are right at home
to
Lord I
[screaming]
Take and see
The fall
might
God.
[music]
Heat.
Yeah.
[music]
Heat.
Hey,
[music]
Heat
up
[music]
here.
Heat
[music]
up here.
>> [applause]
>> Here at [music] Living Mana, we bear
each other's burdens. When you need
support or prayer, when you're [music]
feeling discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to [music] face life
struggles alone.
Heat. Heat.
Let us come boldly unto the [music]
throne of grace that we may obtain mercy
and find grace to help in our time of
need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves [music] those who are crushed
in spirit.
Amen. Amen. Greetings, Living Mana
family, saints of the most high God, and
our first-time visitors. Welcome to
another edition of Living Mana's prayer
and praise time. And we just want to
start off today. I'm brother Terry. This
is my lovely bride Amra. We're happy to
be back with you. And we just want to
remind you, you are a chosen generation,
a royal priesthood, a holy nation, and a
peculiar kind of people that you should
show forth the praises of him who has
called us out of darkness into his
marvelous light. Welcome, welcome,
welcome. Listen, and speaking of showing
forth praises, Oakwood and the Aolans, I
mean, they just lift the roof off that
place today with that praise. Come thou
fountain. Saw y'all praising him in the
chat. That was something to praise God
about. I mean, they lifted it up in
there.
>> And so, hallelujah. Hallelujah. And we
can do it right here, saints. We can
lift it up. Remember to hit that like
button. Remember to share the link. And
uh let's give God some glory. Hey y'all,
I see you in the chat. We just want to
shout out a few people. First, I want to
start with my beloved brother, Elder
Robert E. Plant. God bless you. Love
you. Who he's actually our powerline
programmer now and he's helping things
run smoothly there. We love you. Sister
Nicole and the rest of the crew. Love
y'all too.
>> Everybody,
>> Christie, Clint, Ayanna.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> John, Jamie, Mon'nique,
>> I love what she said. She Monip said he
is able. Yes, he is able. He is able. I
am Rain.
>> Hey Christy in South Carolina, we see
you there beloved. Amen. Every
>> Takara.
>> Sister Takara. All right there, Sister
Takara. Keep on lifting him up.
>> Black Rob. It is
>> That's Elder Robert E. Plan.
>> Well, hello Robert. Oh, it is so well
with my soul.
>> Amen. Who said that? It is so well with
my soul. Hallelujah. Y'all are a
blessing. Y'all a blessing.
>> Thank you, Dot, for your compliment.
Sister Dodd, love you. Love you.
[laughter] Love you. Everybody, yes.
Yes. Look, some of y'all, we don't have
to wait for your comments to come up to
shout you out in here today. Want to
shout out all of the living man of
prayer warriors, all of our hosts, all
of our facilitators, all of our
scripture readers, all of our singers.
Uh, Sister Barbara, what a blessing you
are. I hope you're watching, Sister
Barbara. You are blessing. you and the
Fab 7, Brother Kirk, let me tell you, I
mean, just they were they were a
blessing the other night. The Fab 7 is
Papa Ronnie uh special ops prayer team
and they came on and I mean y'all just
such a blessing. Thank you so much for
hosting. Brother Elco, you know, you
were my man Elco. We were talking
earlier today before we started. Just so
many I don't want to be
>> Yes, Ayanna. It's a mini roll call. Yes,
it is. Hello, Llaya Peterson. Hello,
Nicole Curtis. No. Yes, everybody.
Sister Ayana,
>> love you, my sister. What a blessing you
are. And
>> the right stuff.
>> Sister Annette, you you've done such a
wonderful job. Sister Annette blessed us
up one side and down the other this this
uh 10 days of prayer and always you work
so hard living mana and we love you and
we love you. Love you. May God continue
to bless you and your family. And um
also, Sister Blessing, was good to see
you, Sister Blessing. You know, I'm
going to be reaching out to you now.
Hallelujah. Love you so much for
everything here.
>> An amazing time with Shaunine and Denise
and Jackie.
>> I'm getting to them.
>> And it's been actually a two or three
weeks since we've been able to sit
together here to do praise and prayer
time.
>> But that doesn't mean I haven't been on
the phone with Denise. I mean, of
course.
>> Yeah, I know. I'm just saying I miss
sitting next to you. I appreciate the I
love my wife mug that you have put in my
place
>> when I'm not here. [laughter]
>> Yes. Glad to have the mug. All right.
So, happy Sabbath, saints. Hope that
you're blessed. Hope that you've been
blessed by the Lord today. His presence
and the word and the fellowship that
we've had. I'm going [snorts] to tell
you something. God is doing something so
special, y'all. Let's keep on pressing
on. Let's keep on studying and staying
in the word of God. You know, we hear a
lot of messages. I was just going
through this morning again through the
living mana playlist and part of the
limb playlist and stuff. Pastor Myers,
God is just pouring the word in and
through this mighty vessel. Let's
remember to keep him and the first lady
lifted up. First lady be getting on fire
preaching herself, right? So, let's just
keep them lifted up with the amazing
work that they're doing. I know that you
who got a chance to join us last night
for the story of the T horns, you had to
be blessed. Look at here. I mean, when
the way that thing unfolded and I can
say all of us, yeah, we we always went
through the T horns and just got on past
that and focused on the little horn. But
the Lord like like first lady was saying
last night, the Lord doesn't put
anything in the word of God for nothing.
There's a purpose for it all. And so the
spirit of the Lord has led the pastor to
just go back and say, "Look, let's focus
on these horns one at a time. Each one,
what were they doing?
>> What was going on? what was the most
predominant characteristic of each of
these ruling parties or horns at the
time. And we're seeing God is showing us
in that 10th horn, that last horn, we're
going to see a culmination of all of
that. And so it can be a little bit
scary, a little bit overwhelming at
first until we sit back and think, wait
a minute, where he leads, where he
guides, he always provides. So if he's
showing us that, he's already made
provision for it. So let's rejoice and
tell the world. watched it, go back to
Power of the Lamb Ministries on YouTube
and check out the
>> 10 horns. Um,
>> you got to see it. You got to share it.
And again, remember, our God is good.
Somebody ought to shout it. God is a
good God. If he's shown us, look, I know
this is coming, then we know he's also
made provision to provide for us through
it. See, that's some good stuff. He
ain't going to just tell this is coming.
I don't know what you going to do when
it get there. But no, God has already
made provision for us. So let us stay in
step with him. Walk by faith. You learn
to fight blindfolded as Pastor Anatante
shared with us today. What a mighty God
we serve. All right, we're going to do
praise reports.
>> Praise report.
>> We're getting a little worked up there.
We want to get a little, you know, you
know, I can't wait to get together with
y'all because I already know this bunch
right here. This is a shout hallelujah.
Good time. Praise the Lord. There's
nothing like meeting people face to face
and being able to hug them in person. I
hope we get the opportunity to do that
soon.
>> I know it is. You know what? I want to
hug my sister Pauline. I want to hug all
y'all, right? But Sister Pauline, let me
tell you something. Encouraging me every
day. I love you. Yeah, I know you
thought I wasn't going to shout you out,
but I'm gonna shout you out. Love you.
John, I see you there. Uh just
everybody. Clint, God bless you, my
brother. Always, always, always. Yes,
MT, my voice is finally back.
>> Yes, it is. Now, look, [laughter]
two of two of two people we just
absolutely love so much. Thank y'all for
always being like our ram in the
thicket, you know, our just our aces,
our brother and sister, always on the
battlefield. Let me tell you, fire all
the time. Brother Danny and sister
Jackie. Yes,
>> we love y'all. I know y'all wonder, you
No way. No way we would forget you. We
love you so much. Amen. Amen. Amen.
Everybody, brother James Haley, I don't
know if you're watching, but I love you,
man. You were a blessing hearing you
pray this week. Always a blessing,
everybody.
>> Takara, I hope to hug you in person. For
sure.
>> Amen. Brother Cash, brother Kashif, I
see you there, brother. Thank you for
singing for us this week. Always was
always a blessing. Beautiful stuff. Wow.
Who's the first timer?
>> Bought with a price 777.
Welcome to Living Mana.
>> Welcome, beloved. Wow. Come on, y'all.
Give a a nice living mana. Welcome to
Bought with a Price. Beautiful. Thank
you that you for joining us today,
worshiping with us. Hope that you are
blessed. Stay tuned for a mighty word
from the pastor. Also, when we're done,
there's the afterglow. Elder U uh Robert
E. Plant's going to be hosting the
afterlow. We get together, fellowship,
spend time together, talk about what we
heard doing Sabbath school and the
sermon. And uh it's always a blessing
and and you can get plugged in, find out
what's going on at Living Man. There's a
lot going on here. I'm going to tell
y'all something.
>> We've been in local churches, you know,
where, you know, they've had small
groups and prayer meetings and all these
different things going on. I'm going to
tell you, for an online church, living
man be having it going on all the time,
every day. Get plugged in. You'll see
>> our prayer our prayer meetings
off the chain. Can I say that?
>> Hood really on fire because God has
really put something together and he's
continuing to put it together. So come
join us. We're going to need more prayer
warriors, y'all. I'm going to tell you,
God has got up something. He talk about
let him cook. God is cooking up
something powerful. Morning and evening
mana. Pray about that. Where do you see
what it is? We need more prayer warriors
to man that thing. That thing is going
to be something. And you know, we have
the blueprint. We know we talk about the
sanctuary here a lot. We learned to pray
through the sanctuary. Our men's
ministry is built on the principles of
the sanctuary. I mean, the women's
ministry was doing some powerful stuff
at the sanctuary. We believe thy way, oh
Lord, is in the sanctuary here. We
believe that, you know, that there's
everything we need to know about how to
live this life and walk with God is in
that sanctuary. But saints, let me tell
you, morning and evening sacrifices were
offered up at the sanctuary. Think about
this morning and evening mana. I'm not
going to give it away, but I want you to
pray and ask God, God should do I do you
want me to join the ring of the living
man of prayer ministry. Let me tell you
saints what he's got in store.
[clears throat]
>> What we've been doing with these
breakout rooms during the 10 days of
prayer, we're going to always have going
on during uh our power Wednesdays,
right?
>> But morning and evening prayer, where do
you see what God's working on? Love
y'all. Love y'all. Love y'all. Pray for
us. Amen.
Okay, beloved.
>> Okay, [laughter]
[gasps]
>> if you have just some announcements
before I go into praise reports. If you
have a prayer request or a praise report
that you would like to submit to us and
they your prayers will be prayed over
throughout the week and I will read your
praise report on our weekly broadcast.
Please send an email to praymanana.urch.
church.
If you would like to join the prayer
team, as Terry was just recruiting for,
you would not regret it. Our prayer team
has some amazing members in it. It is
such a community of love and hope and
encouragement.
Um, please also send an email to
praymana.urch.
>> Amen. If you would like to request a
special ops prayer team for you or a
loved one, please send an email to spec
ops at living manana.urch.
Oh, awesome. There is a graphic for
that. Um, if you need a midweek pickup,
please join us for Power Wednesdays.
It's so awesome because we either have a
devotional every week or we have um a
personal testimony from one of our
members and that takes place at 4:30
p.m. Pacific Standard Time, 6:30
Central, 7:30 Eastern. And following
that is the power line every Wednesday
at 6:00 PM Pacific Standard Time, 8:00
PM Central, and 900 PM Eastern Standard
Time. You can um find that live taking
your live prayer requests on YouTube.
If you would like to join the women's
ministry, please send an email to women
at living mana.urch.
They are on mighty networks and they are
a very uh active group. If you would
like to join the men's ministry, please
send an email to men
livingmana.urch
church and you can connect with other
males going through the things that you
all identify with.
>> Amen.
>> All right.
Now for the praise reports.
The first one coming from Francis Grant.
God is a miracle working God. family. A
few days ago, I had asked that all would
keep our family in prayer as we were
planning to remove the life life support
equipment on this Monday for my nephew
Randy, who was involved in a
life-threatening car accident. He had
been on life support since the accident
occurred, showing no signs of
communication or brain activity. On
Tuesday morning, the medical team was
about to move Randy to the location to
do the removal procedure.
One of the team, for no reason at all,
suggested that they do one more test.
Please note that they had been doing
continual testing up until this moment
with no response or action from Randy.
But the team agreed to do one more test
and they administered the pain test.
Family, because of your prayers, because
of who God is, by his omnipotent power,
Ry's leg in response to the pain.
Randy is still alive. They will not be
completely removing the life support
equipment, but will be changing the
support used to help him breathe from
the ventilator to another apparatus and
will continue to monitor monitor him,
but know that the Lord decided that. And
here is the update.
Our life and times are in the hands of
the Lord. He who knows the end from the
beginning does all things well. Our
father has ordained that his child, my
nephew Randy, takes his rest until Jesus
returns.
>> I thank the Lord for the opportunity
that he provided for us to remind Randy
that the Lord loved him. Letting go is
hard for many members of the family.
Please keep us lifted up in prayer.
Thank you, Francis. We are absolutely
keeping you in prayer and we just thank
you for praising throughout this whole
experience with your nephew.
>> Amen.
>> I can't imagine what a deep loss that is
for you and your family. But we love you
and we will keep you in prayer.
>> Amen.
>> From Takara Bumpus,
happy Sabbath church family. God is
faithful. He is a prayer answering God.
On Wednesday on the power line with
sister Amara and brother Terry, that was
probably two or three weeks ago I think.
I put in a prayer request for a dear
friend of mine, Van Cox, and his oldest
daughter, Jasmine, who has been sitting
in jail for two months while pregnant
for a misunderstanding.
She had been waiting to see a judge and
waiting for them to set a bond. And the
other day she started bleeding and
thought she might be losing the baby
>> and was asking to be taken to the
hospital and they kept delaying.
>> Finally they had to get her proper care
and send her to the hospital and I'm
happy to say the baby is okay.
>> Praise God. But on Friday, her dad
called and told me that jail, where
she's been held, and the bail bonds men
are going to put up the bond that was
over $4,000 to release her because they
are afraid of a lawsuit. She's only
having to pay $400 to wear an ankle
monitor instead of paying $4,000.
She will be released on Tuesday. Thank
you, church family, for your prayers. I
told Van that it was the prayers of my
church family that God heard our prayers
on behalf of your daughter and they have
to open up those jail doors. Just like
God did it for Peter, he did it for
Jasmine.
>> James 5:16. The effectual fervent prayer
of a righteous man avaleth much.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> From Evet Ausu. Auso. I'm sorry for the
misprononunciation.
Good morning, my beloved familia. Today,
my nephew Damiani goes before the judge
to see if he will be vindicated from a
felony for false charges that he hit a
cop and resisted arrest.
>> He's never been in trouble with the law.
The goal is to drop the charges to a
misdemeanor because he was intoxicated.
Thank you for your prayers
>> and the praise update. Update on my
nephew Damiani. God is mighty and
merciful. The judge dropped the charges
from a felony to a misdemeanor for
resisting arrest and not an attack on a
police officer. He was given probation.
Praise God. Thank you, Familia, for all
of your prayers. So grateful for you
from Shaunene Wright.
Hello Shaunene.
Praise God for his timing. I was
supposed to leave my son's home
yesterday. However, my car was acting up
and I had a vertigo attack. I can't get
it fixed until tomorrow morning. I went
into the quest room and began watching
Doug Bachelor's Armageddon movie.
>> My son walked in and was captivated by
it and watched most of it with me.
>> He said he was going to watch it again.
He and his wife Tiffany are studying the
Bible. I praise God and give him glory.
I will continue to pray for all of our
children's salvation.
>> Amen.
>> And I got to meet them in person. Yes.
So, it was really nice to see her son
and daughter-in-law
>> from Reuben.
I want to give thanks to God and all
prayer warriors. I requested prayer for
my daughter's spiritual life and God is
calling her with love and she is slowly
getting nearer to Jesus more every day.
>> Amen. I remember that one.
>> Yes. From Wendy Allen. Thank you for
praying for Cassie and her children for
so many months. She is divorced. They
found a place to live in time and are
moving forward with life.
>> Amen.
>> From Zadwa.
>> Yes.
>> I want to thank God for coming through
for my daughter. She passed her GCSEs.
Thank you for your prayers. God bless
your ministry. And I also think I saw a
praise report here from
let me find it. Let me find it. Let me
find it. Estraita White.
I can't find it. But I do recall
Estreita putting in the chat that did a
praise report for her hip
>> feeling much better.
>> Well, thank you, Sister Estrea. We do
love you and always praying for you. And
Regina, always love you. Thank you
always.
in prayer [clears throat] for you and
your beautiful family and everyone here.
We thank God for the opportunity to be
able to stand in the gap and pray for
you. Assure you that uh our prayer
warriors, the living man of prayer
warriors are always praying all the
time, even 24-hour prayer and fasting
that we have going on a lot of times and
uh for special needs. And uh I want to I
want to say that I've never seen a more
committed to prayer warriors and and
prayer is God's gift to us. It's our
lifeline to glory. Uh power line we like
to say it's our connection to the
throne. No matter what's going on, we
are plugged in here and we thank God for
it. Mhm.
>> And speaking of prayer, we're getting
ready to go to the throne of grace, but
I want to take the time to introduce to
you uh the next prayer warrior, warrior,
prayer leader, ministry leader, such a
gift to us here at Living Mana. You
know, earlier during Sabbath school, I
mentioned
um the Chiffra and Pua who the Hebrew
midwives that Pharaoh tried to use to
destroy all the male babies of Israel.
But uh these women feared God more than
they did Pharaoh. And even Pharaoh's
daughter fetched Moses out of that
crocodileinfested Nile. And over and
over in the Bible, we see mighty women
of God doing incredible work uh uh uh as
the hand and feet of Jesus, you know,
but as Shipper and Puera has special
significance to me because they were
right before the Exodus that that they
were being used. And right now before
this last great Exodus when Jesus comes
to take his church out of here, I
believe God is using mighty mighty women
of God in a great way. And I just want
to honor all of our women and and
specifically today because this next
warriorette who's coming up is the
leader of the women's ministry. I mean
just a picture of beauty and grace and
professionalism and eloquence and want
to encourage you when to get involved
with the prayer the women's ministry. If
you're not one of the reasons why the
men's ministry really got off the ground
because we were looking over at the
women and we were so inspired by what
they were doing. And we're like, look,
we got brothers, brother, [laughter]
brothers, we got to get up and move
because the women of were just doing so
much in the church and we're seeing it
and we're saying, you know, God is still
using mighty women of God to fetch his
men out of this crocodileinfested world
and to encourage us and stand by us and
and thank y'all all of you who are doing
what you are doing. No matter who you
are, where you are, where you're going
through, where you're married, where
you're single, whatever you're doing in
ministry, thank you women of God. We
love you. And so here I said all that to
introduce to you our sister who's going
to lead us to the throne of grace,
Sister Sheila Isert, who we love and we
thank God for. I mean all the time.
Sister Cila, bless you as you come and
thank you for your service.
All right. Here and and take your time,
Sister Sheila. I know you coming.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> [sighs]
>> Oh, blessing saints and thank you for
that welcome.
God is good and
I just have to praise him. I am so
honored and blessed to intercede on
behalf of the saints this morning. So,
let's pray.
Dear heavenly father,
we praise you for who you are. You are
holy, faithful, and worthy of all of our
praise. From the rising of the sun to
its setting, your name is to be praised,
and we thank you for your goodness, your
mercy, and your unfailing love towards
us. Lord, we ask that you forgive us and
cleanse us from all sin and all
unrighteousness.
Remove every trace of selfishness and
fill us with your love. Lord, we thank
you for carrying us through these past
10 days of prayer as we sought you
together. We've prayed, we've waited,
and we've asked for your Holy Spirit to
be unleashed in our lives, in our homes,
and in this church. Today, we come
trusting that you have heard us and that
you are already at work. Please continue
to move in us and through us.
shape our hearts, renew our minds, and
empower us to live as bold witnesses for
Christ. We lift up our families, our
friends, our loved ones, asking you to
unleash the Holy Spirit into their lives
as well. Loving Father, you see every
request that has been shared, those
written in the chats and even the ones
held quietly in our hearts. You know the
needs of your people and we lift them
all before you now.
For all those facing health challenges,
we ask for your healing touch. We lift
up Marty who is experiencing high fever
and physical weak weakness
following his cancer treatments. Place
your healing hand upon his body. Lower
his temperature. Restore his strength
and bring peace to him and those who
love him. Bring strength to all weak
bodies.
Peace to anxious hearts and comfort all
those who are hurting.
For those carrying family burdens, we
ask for your restoration
and grace. We lift up Sister Shaunin's
children, asking that they make life
decisions that would heed their the
voice, heed your voice and turn away
from sin and worldliness.
We ask that you also be with Tracy and
her family,
asking you to steady them through stormy
winds in their lives.
We ask that you grant Tracy endurance,
strengthen her faith, and surround her
and her tribe with your peace. Bring
unity into all of our families. Where
there is division,
bring patience. Where there's strain and
hearts that trust you and seek your
guidance. For those under financial
pressure, we ask for provision and
wisdom. We lift up Candy who is seeking
housing.
And we ask and all others that are are
dealing with um living situations. We
ask that you open the right doors
according to your will. Grant peace as
they wait
and remind them
that you are the provider and that all
of our needs are safe in your hands.
For those who are facing decisions that
require wisdom, we ask for clear
direction. We lift up Sister Hila and
Wes, asking that your will will be
clearly revealed in their lives as they
trust you for each step ahead. We also
lift up rain who is waiting for answers
and struggling with anxiety and
discouragement.
Cramp patient [clears throat] as she
waits. Quiet fear for thoughts. Replace
those worst case worries with trust in
you and strengthen every heart with
peace and hope. Order their steps, quiet
their minds, and help them to trust your
leading.
For those who are grieving or carrying
broken hearts, we ask for your comfort.
We lift up Moshe who longs for clarity
in spiritual sight.
Open their eyes, awaken a deep desire
for you, and draw them gently into your
truth and light. We also lift up Regina,
her mother, Estelita, and her sister
Renee, and her cousin Jonique. Rekindle
the fire in their hearts. Heal what is
broken. Surround them with your peace
and help them be the light within their
families.
For those experiencing loneliness, we
ask for your presence. Let them feel
seen,
known,
and loved. Place caring people around
them and reassure them that they are
never alone. For those with weary hearts
from the weight of this world all around
them, lift the heaviness we carry.
restore hope and strengthen us with your
peace and the safety of your presence.
We lift up Adah and her family in Iran
whose lives are in danger even in
ordinary moments. Lord, be their refuge,
their protector. We ask for your divine
covering, your intervention, and a
miracle of deliverance. Shine your light
in to the darkness that surrounds them
and bring safety and hope and freedom to
the Persian people who are suffering and
see all the suffering all around this
world and come to their aid.
Lord, we also lift up those who have not
yet come to know you and those who have
wandered away from you. We lift up
Astasha and Dawn's families, asking that
they come to know you fully.
We also pray for Hunter, that he is
being guided through your word. His
heart and his mind will be open to
truth, prophecy, and your leading. We
also place in your hands those who have
been receiving Bible studies or have
been given books or tracks so that they
know you more. We meet each We ask that
you meet each one where they are. Let
them encounter your grace, hear your
voice, and find their way to you. Find
their way home.
Heavenly Father, we place all of these
needs in your hands. See the requests in
the chat that I have missed. We trust
you to work according to your will and
in your perfect timing. Strengthen
strengthen our faith as we wait on you.
As we continue in worship today, prepare
our hearts to receive your word. May
everything said and done bring honor and
glory to your name. We thank you, we
praise you, and we trust you.
In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
>> [music]
>> There's nothing worth more [singing]
that [music] will ever come close.
Nothing can compare.
You're our [music and singing] living
hope.
your [music] presence,
Lord. [singing]
I've tasted [singing] and seen
of the sweetest [music] of loves
where my heart becomes free
and my shame is undone
[music]
in your presence [singing]
Lord.
[music]
Holy [music] Spirit, you are welcome
[singing] here. Comfort [music]
this place and fill the atmosphere.
[singing]
[music]
Your glory,
God, is what our [singing] hearts
[music] long for. To be overcome
by [music] your presence, [singing]
Lord.
your [singing] presence,
[music]
Oh,
there's nothing [music] worth more
that will ever come close.
Nothing [music] can compare.
You're [singing] our living hope.
your presence
Lord. [singing and music]
Oh Lord, Holy Spirit,
Holy [music]
Spirit, [singing] you are welcome
here. Come [music] flood this place and
fill the atmosphere. [singing]
Your glory,
God, is what our [singing] hearts long
for. to be overcome
by your presence,
Lord.
Your [singing] presence,
Oh,
let's become more aware of your [music]
presence.
Let us experience the glory of your
goodness.
Let us [music and singing] become more
aware of your presence.
Let's experience [music] the glory of
your goodness.
Let's become [music]
more aware of your presence.
Let's experience [music]
the glory of your goodness.
Let's become more aware of your
presence.
Let's [music] experience
the glory [singing]
of your goodness.
Holy Spirit,
Holy Spirit, [singing] you are welcome
here. Come flood this place and fill
[music] the atmosphere.
[singing]
Your glory,
God, is [music] what our hearts long
for. to be overcome
by your [music and singing] presence,
Lord.
[singing]
Your presence,
Lord. [music]
Oh,
your presence, Lord. [singing]
Amen. Amen. Happy Sabbath everyone.
Welcome. Uh we are going to be [cough]
[clears throat]
getting into the word of God
this morning. So, if you are ready to
receive the living mana, please go ahead
and put that one in the chat.
We're going to seat the Lord's face in
prayer [clears throat]
and um hear what he has to say to us
today from his word. So, let's pray.
Heavenly Father,
Lord, I ask in a special way today that
you would again speak to your people,
Lord. Um, may the message that is shared
today be fresh
mana from heaven. May it fill our souls.
I pray in Jesus name. Amen. Amen. Um,
can you guys hear me? Put a one in the
chat if you could hear me. Just want to
make sure that we're good.
To get today, guys, we are going to be
looking at this theme of the house of
David. The house of David. Let's go to
the screen.
And um
to begin this message, I want to give
you a little context. I want to give you
a little context.
And [clears throat]
the the the
place that we will begin this message
today
um is a verse that is so
rich and pregnant with meaning. Um it
will be our main focus. It will be the
main verse.
If you don't remember anything else,
remember this verse as we pull it up on
the screen. So, let's go to the screen
once again. The title of the sermon, the
house of David. The house of David. And
we will begin
with 2 Samuel 3 and verse 1.
The Bible says here, "Now there was long
war between the house of Saul and the
house of David, but David waxed stronger
and stronger, and the house of Saul
waxed weaker and weaker." Now, I'm going
to say this.
I feel like we can already say amen and
be done with the message. I feel
[clears throat]
that that if you are in tune with the
Holy Spirit,
you may already
be saying to yourself, "Amen." This is
it. This is the message right here. What
a powerful verse. Now, I do not mean to
to to suggest that if you do not
understand yet that you are not in tune
with the Holy Spirit. Not at all.
But we're going to break it down
regardless. We're going to break it down
regardless. So, um let's let's begin
with some context because there's some
story there's a story behind this war.
Uh this this story is is significant.
Let's go uh back to the book of 1st
Samuel chapter 10 or 1st Samuel um uh
sec I'm sorry 1st Samuel chapter 15.
We're going to go back one verse. I'm
sorry you guys. We we'll read 1st Samuel
chapter 10. And it's not up on the
screen, but I'm going to read it in your
hearing. Then Samuel took a small
container of olive oil and poured it on
Saul's head.
Samuel kissed him and said, "The Lord
has chosen you to lead his people
Israel, and you will rule over uh you
will rule over the Lord's people, and
you will deliver them from the power of
the enemies who surround you. This will
be your sign that the Lord has chosen
you as leader over his inheritance." For
a little bit of background about this
war between the house of David and the
house of Saul, we first need to
understand that Saul comes on the screen
as a person that has been anointed by
God [clears throat]
to serve Israel to be the king of
Israel.
But as the story of Saul continues, what
we'll find is that Saul begins to rebel
against God. And this rebellion gets so
deep and so thick that we get to the
place where we read in 1st Samuel 15:28.
And Samuel said unto him, that is Saul,
"The Lord has rent the kingdom of Israel
from thee this day, and has given it to
a neighbor of thine that is better than
thou." And so this is our introduction
[clears throat]
to David. This is our introduction to
David. We do not yet know who David is.
That is coming up. But in this story,
Saul, who was first anointed and used of
God, then is rejected of God. And and
God is going to choose David to reign in
Saul's place. And so we find in 1st
Samuel chapter 16:13,
the Bible says, "Then Samuel took the
horn of oil and anointed him, that is
David, in the midst of his brethren. So
the spirit of the Lord came upon David
from that day forward. So Samuel rose up
and went to Rama." I want you to
understand that as David is anointed,
the Bible says that the spirit of the
Lord came upon him from that day
forward. So David has now been anointed,
but Saul is still the king. We will
remember
that David gets his moment of truth when
he goes to face the giant Goliath. David
kills the giant Goliath and and he
fights where Saul should have been the
one fighting. So David kills Goliath and
the people are rejoicing and they see
David as a hero. But something begins to
happen in 1st Samuel 18:9.
The Bible says, "And Saul was very
wroth, and the saying displeased him, as
he said, they have ascribed unto David
10 thousands, and to me they have
ascribed but thousands. And what can he
have more but the kingdom?"
What can he have more but the kingdom?
And Saul eyed David from that day
forward.
So, get the [clears throat] picture
here. Saul is now eyeing David. I did a
whole sermon one time uh about Saul
eyeing David. That evil eye, that evil
look, that evil view of a brother, of a
fellow believer. Here, Saul eyes David
from that day forward. Why? Because
David
is going to be the man who takes the
place of Saul. You guys,
I need you to, if you're taking notes,
write that in your notes. David takes
the place of Saul. David takes the place
of Saul. Listen to what the Bible says
here in 1st Samuel 16:14.
But the spirit of the Lord departed from
Saul, and an evil spirit from the Lord
troubled him. Again, 1st Samuel 19:9 and
10. And the evil spirit from the Lord
was upon Saul as he sat in his house
with his javelin in his hand. And David
played with his hand. And Saul sought to
smite David even to the wall with the
javelin. But he slipped away out of
Saul's presence. and the and he smoked
the javelin into the wall and David fled
and escaped by night. And so what I want
you to see here, beloved, what I want
you to see here is that Saul is now
attempting to kill David.
Put that in the chat for me, please.
Saul is attempting to kill David. Listen
to me carefully. David takes the place
of Saul.
Saul does not want that. So Saul is
attempting to kill David. The Bible says
in 1st Samuel 18 verse 29, "And Saul was
yet the more afraid of David, and Saul
became David's enemy." How long
everybody?
Continually.
Saul became David's enemy. continually.
It was a perpetual
hatred.
If you're with me so far, put a one in
the chat. We are just building the
foundation for why that verse at the
beginning is so powerful and so relevant
to us today.
And so because [clears throat] Saul is
is continually trying to kill David, the
Bible tells us in 1st Samuel 23:14, "And
David abode in the wilderness in the
strongholds and remained in a mountain
in the wilderness of Ze." And Saul
sought him every day, but God delivered
him not into his hand. Wow. Wow. This is
powerful, you guys. We are still laying
a a foundation here because once you see
and understand your minds are going to
may your minds
be changed
from this day forward as you understand
this powerful and absolutely amazing
truth. While David is away in hiding,
the Bible says in 1st Samuel 23,
1st Samuel 23 and verse 14, all these
men of war that could keep rank came
with a perfect heart to Hebron to make
David king over Israel, and all the rest
also of Israel were of one mind to make
David king. So this verse is basically
telling us beloved that throughout
David's journey, he was continually
receiving uh men of war, men of valor
who understood that he was to be king
and they were they were behind him in
this. You are the one that is going to
take the place of David. And now we have
laid the foundation. We have set the
groundwork for the rest of this message.
And what I want you to see, beloved, is
that everything you just heard,
everything that you just heard is a
powerful and mighty parallel
[clears throat]
object lesson,
parable.
So that when you understand this in its
depth
by the grace of God, you will be
encouraged
because of what you hear. Pastor, what
are you saying? Come with me to Jeremiah
chapter 23:5
where the Bible says, "Behold, the days
come, sayeth the Lord, that I will raise
unto David a righteous branch, and a
king shall reign and prosper, and shall
execute judgment and justice in the
earth." Let me pause for a second.
You see, when the text that we read
earlier stated that the house of David
grew stronger and stronger and the house
of Saul grew weaker and weaker. What I
want you to understand, beloved, is
this. We look at that verse. And if
you're familiar with the story, you're
probably thinking to yourself, "Yeah,
that's referring to David in his day and
Saul in his day. And as they are are as
they are uh h um as this conflict is
going on for the throne, David's house
is getting stronger and stronger until
he gets the throne. And Saul's house is
getting weaker and weaker. And that's
where we kind of stop the story. But
beloved, what I need you to understand
is that the house of David goes beyond
the days of David. Let me say it again,
beloved. The house of David goes beyond
the days of David. Jeremiah 23:5 tells
us that of the house of David, God would
raise up a righteous branch, a king unto
the throne of David. Meaning that not
only would David's house get stronger
and stronger through David ascending the
throne, but even after his death, listen
to me you guys,
even after his death, the
[clears throat] house of David would
continue to grow stronger and stronger.
Why? Because Jesus,
who would be of the house of David,
would ultimately come to this earth and
live a perfect life and then ascend as
Luke 1 verse 32 tells us, he shall be
great and shall be called the son of the
highest. And the Lord God shall give
unto him the throne of David his father.
Beloved, the reason why this verse that
we opened with is so significant to us
is because it does not end with the
death of David. It continues on. The
house of David would grow would grow
stronger even after the death of David.
Why? Because one would come who would be
the king prophesied raised up unto the
throne of David. Are y'all with me so
far? Therefore, beloved, therefore, when
we read the house of David, we really
ought to be seeing in this verse that
Jesus is the ultimate fulfillment of the
house of David. Here, let me explain to
you on a deeper level if I may. In
Genesis chapter 3:15,
1st Samuel chapter 3 verse one is
amplified because the Bible says here, I
will put enmity between thee
and the woman,
between thy seed and her seed. It shall
bruise thy head, and thou shalt bruise
his heel. Please understand with me,
beloved, that what Genesis 3:15 is
telling us is that there would be two
houses. There would be two two streams,
two lineages like we spoke about last
week in our sermon. There would be two
streams. And and in 2 Samuel 3:1, what
we find is the manifestation of these
two streams, these two houses. In other
words, we may read Genesis 3:15 in this
way. I will put enmity between thee, the
house of Saul, and the woman, the house
of David. Between thy seed, and her
seed, the house of Saul, and the house
of David. And listen to me, the house of
David will bruise thy head, but the
house of Saul would bruise thy heel. In
other words, the house of David would
grow stronger while the house of Saul
would grow weaker. If you're with me so
far,
put that one in the chat. Let me break
it down for you even more. You see, like
Saul,
like Saul, the leader of the house of
Saul was also once anointed. Ezekiel
[snorts]
28:14 and 15 tells us this. Thou art the
anointed cherub that coverereth, and I
have made thee so. Thou was upon the
holy mountain of God. Thou hast walked
up and down in the midst of the stones
of fire. Thou was perfect in thy ways
from the day that thou was created until
iniquity was found in thee. Please
understand that just as Saul was once
anointed but then lost favor with God,
so the leader of the house of Saul was
also once anointed. Lucifer himself
also once anointed but lost favor with
God. Now, why is that so significant?
Because thousands of years later, we
have a man by the name of Jesus Christ.
In Matthew 3:3 and 14, the Bible tells
us, "Then cometh Jesus from Galilee to
Jordan unto John to be baptized unto
him." But John forbade him, saying, I
have need to be baptized of thee, and
comest thou to me?
Let me come back
and I'll read verse 15 and 16. In your
hearing, Jesus answered and said, "Suff
it to be so now. For for thus it
becometh us to fulfill all
righteousness." Then he suffered him.
And Jesus, when he was baptized, went up
straightway out of the water, and lo,
the heavens were opened unto him, and he
saw the spirit of God descending like a
dove and lighting upon him, and lo, a
voice from heaven, saying, "This is my
beloved son in whom I am well pleased."
So please note, just as David comes on
the scene later and is anointed,
so Jesus in the flesh comes on the scene
and is anointed. Why? Because while
Satan is the current king of this earth,
Jesus has been anointed to take his
place.
rulership away from him.
And then how interesting how interesting
that just as David defeated Goliath
by [snorts] delivering a blow to the
head.
So we have Jesus
in Matthew 27 and verse 33. The Bible
says,
"And when they were come to a place
called Golgtha, that is to say the place
of a skull." Matthew 27:33, "Jesus is
now being crucified at a place called
Goltha, meaning the place of the skull."
Please follow along with me you guys as
I want you to understand that in Genesis
3:15 when the Bible says that that Jesus
would bruise the head of the serpent
that this is literally being fulfilled
at Goltha where Jesus when he dies on
that skull-shaped hill when he dies on
that place that is called Calvary
meaning cranon in the Greek or Goltha
the place of the skull know that Jesus
is symbolically showing his victory over
Satan in that moment.
Now,
you'll remember that after David defeats
Goliath
that a great multitude
start coming to David because they know
that he is to be the rightful king.
Beloved, in the very same way in the
book of Acts 2:1, the Bible says, "When
the day of Pentecost was fully come,
they were all with one accord in one
place. And suddenly there came a sound
from heaven as of a rushing mighty wind,
and it filled all the house where they
were sitting. And there appeared unto
them cloven tongues like as a fire, and
it sat upon each one of them." Acts 2:41
says, "Then they that gladly received
his word were baptized, and the same day
there were added unto them 3,000 souls."
Please check out the powerful parallel.
Just as many began coming to David after
he defeats Goliath, after he defeats
this giant, just as many begin coming to
David because they know that he is to be
the rightful king. So after Jesus
defeats Satan at the cross by delivering
a deadly blow to the head of the serpent
Goltha Calvary Cranon. Jesus now having
ascended into heaven now has people
multitudes 3,000 in one day coming to
him which again reveals something
powerful y'all.
Because when those soldiers, listen to
me, when those soldiers
decided to join David,
what they were actually doing was
becoming a part of the house of David.
Let me say it again.
Everyone who went to join David
became a part of the house of David. Let
me say the verse again.
There was a long war,
a great controversy
between the house of David and the house
of Saul. But the house of David grew
stronger and stronger, and the house of
Saul grew weaker and weaker. You guys,
this thing is like a prophecy.
It's almost as if the prophecy is
telling us, listen, if you are through
Jesus Christ part of the house of David,
it is prophesied that the house of David
grows stronger and stronger while the
house of Saul grows weaker and weaker.
Beloved, that is good news.
That is good news. Now, I need you to
understand, wait a minute. If David
isn't hiding in the wilderness, how can
he be how could the house of David be
growing stronger anyway? And the reason,
beloved, is because God was with David
in the wilderness.
And just as God was with David in the
wilderness, beloved, you will also note,
[clears throat] you will also see in
Revelation 12:6,
that after the death, burial, and
resurrection [clears throat] of Jesus
Christ
and after multitudes begin coming onto
Jesus because of his victory, you find
this period of time that the church
or might I say The house of David or
might I say the woman
is in the wilderness.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Revelation 12:6. And the
woman fled into the wilderness where she
has a place prepared of God that they
should feed her there a,23
score days.
You do understand that the reason she is
in the wilderness for 1,23
score days is because so the house of
Saul is after her.
Revelation 12:13. And when the dragon
saw that he was cast out onto the earth,
he persecuted the woman which brought
forth the manchild. And to the woman
were given two great wings of an eagle
that she might fly into the wilderness
into her place where she is nourished
for a time times and half a time from
the face of the serpent. What I want you
to understand beloved is that when we
see this verse saying that the house of
David grew stronger and stronger while
the house of Saul grew weaker and
weaker. What I need you to understand
beloved is that if you have accepted
Christ as your savior, you are now a
part of the house of David.
And if you are part of the house of
David, you guys,
a prophecy has already been set out for
you that you by the grace of God will
grow stronger and stronger as time goes
on. Oh man.
Wait, what?
What?
Listen, listen, listen. Zechariah 12:8,
"In that day the Lord will protect the
inhabitants of Jerusalem, and the one
who is feeble among them in that day
will be like David, and the house of
David will be like God, like the angel
of the Lord before them." Do you
understand? Do you understand what I'm
trying to say to you today?
The house of David grows stronger and
stronger. And perhaps the reason why
many of us do not grow stronger and
stronger is because we do not realize
that there is a prophecy that states
that you grow stronger and it's
prophecy.
It is a parallel prophecy. It is an
object lesson. It is a it is a it is a
parable that says those in the house of
David will grow stronger and stronger.
And beloved, when we read the prophecy
and understand it, we're like, wait a
minute, God's prophecy,
God's prophecy must come to pass. And if
I walk in faith in that prophecy, then
what he's telling me is that I by the
grace of God as part of the house of
David will grow stronger and stronger.
Listen to me. Isaiah chapter 22:22. And
the key of the house of David will I lay
upon his shoulder so that he shall open
and none shall shut. And he shall shut
and none shall open. Here's what I need
you to understand, beloved.
Jesus
has the key to the house of David.
Meaning he has the the key to open the
door to let you in. And if you are in
the house of David, you are part of a
prophetic word that has been spoken that
you will become stronger. Listen.
Zechariah 12:10. And I will pour upon
the house of David. I will pour upon the
house of David. I will pour upon the
house of David. Do y'all catch this? If
you are in the house of David, you are
going to receive this thing that is
poured out upon the house of David. I
will pour upon the house of David and
and upon the inhabitants of Jerusalem
the spirit of grace and supplication,
and they shall look upon me whom they
have pierced, and they shall mourn for
him as one mourneth for his only son,
and shall be in bitterness for him, as
one that is in bitterness for his
firstborn. Again, Zechariah 13:1, in
that day there shall be a fountain open
to who? to those who are in the house of
David and to the inhabitants of
Jerusalem for unc for sin and
uncleanness. Meaning beloved,
if you are a part of the house of David,
you have access, if you have, if the key
has been used to open the door for you
to be in the house of David, then in the
house of David, there is a fountain
for cleansing.
A fountain for cleansing from sin and
uncleanness. Meaning, wait a minute.
This is how the house of David grows
stronger and stronger because they're in
the place where the fountain
is made available
and it's a prophecy that is stating
it is a prophecy beloved of your future
and my future. If you are in the house
of David, you get swallowed up in that
stream of prophecy that says, "You will
be cleansed. I will make you righteous.
I will purify you. I will make you
stronger and stronger in the grace of
the Lord." The book of Acts 15:1 16 says
it this way. After this, I will return
and I will rebuild the tabernacle of
David which has fallen down and I will
build its ruins and will set it up. Hm.
the tabernacle of David. Could it be
possible that the house of David is the
same thing as the tabernacle of David?
Meaning when God says, "Let them make me
a sanctuary that I may dwell among
them." What he's saying is those who are
in the sanctuary, those who are in the
house of God will grow stronger
continually. Why? Because I'm going to
rebuild the tabernacle.
Not only am I going to rebuild the
tabernacle, but there will be a stream
flowing in that tabernacle for sin and
uncleanness.
And now it begins to make sense why in 1
Peter chapter 2:5, the Bible says, "You
also as living stones are built up a
spiritual house, a holy priesthood to
offer up spiritual sacrifices acceptable
to God through Jesus Christ." And it may
also be why Ephesians 2:19 tells us,
"Now therefore, you are no longer
strangers and foreigners, but fellow
citizens with the saints and members of
the household of God, having been built
upon the foundation of the apostles and
prophets, Jesus Christ himself being the
chief cornerstone." Are y'all following
this? Are y'all following this? in whom
we have the whole building being fitted
together, growing into the a holy temple
in the Lord, in whom also you are being
built together for a dwelling place of
God in the spirit. So you see,
when the Bible tells us that the house
of David grew stronger and stronger,
what it's telling us, beloved, in
parallel form, in parable form, in
object lesson form, is that all those
who are in the house of David will grow
stronger as time goes on. So much so
that by the very end of time, the house
of David will be so strong while the
house of Saul will be so weak. Are y'all
following what I'm saying? Are y'all
catching this? God's people will grow
stronger and stronger as time goes on.
Listen, I know the world is growing
weaker and weaker, wickeder and wicider,
more wicked, more wicked, more wicked as
time goes on. But God says, listen,
that's the house of Saul.
The house of Saul will get weaker,
meaning they will become more and more
wicked as time goes on. But the house of
David will wax stronger and stronger.
And now the question becomes what house
am I a part of? Am I a part of the house
of David or am I a part of the house of
Saul?
And you see now beloved now this becomes
a very personal question because now the
question is how do I personally get into
the house of David and the Bible tells
us the Bible tells us in John 3:es 3 and
4 Jesus replied saying I tell you the
solemn truth unless a person is born
from above he cannot see the kingdom of
God. Nicodemus saith unto him, how can a
man be born when he's old? Can he enter
his mother's womb and be born a second
time? Uh, it goes on to say, Jesus said,
um, verily I say unto you, or I tell you
solemnly, unless a person is born of
water and the spirit, he cannot enter
the kingdom of God. What is born of the
flesh is flesh, and what is born of the
spirit is spirit. Now, I need you to
understand, beloved, that you have two
options here. be either being born of
the flesh or being born of the spirit.
If you are born of the flesh,
that is being the house of Saul.
The house of Saul is symbolic of being
born of the flesh. The house of David is
symbolic of being born of the spirit.
And now I'm bringing this down. I'm
bringing this close to us. But because
here's what I want you to understand. In
every one of us is the house of David
and the house of Saul. [laughter]
Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Every one of us
who have been born of the flesh are a
part of the house of Saul.
But in order to become a part of the
house of David, you have to be born
again. But I need you to understand that
when you're born again, beloved, there
are two natures now within you. There
are two lineages now within you. Note
with me Galatians 5:14. Galatians 5:14.
The Bible says here, in fact, I'm going
to go back and look, we're going to look
at Romans chapter 7 24 where the Bible
says this, "Oh wretched man that I am,
who shall deliver me from the body of
the of this death?" I thank God through
Jesus Christ our Lord. So then with the
mind I myself serve the law of God, but
with the flesh the law of sin. Did y'all
catch that?
With the flesh, the law of sin.
There's a battle going on. There is a
battle going on within each one of us.
The Bible says in Romans chapter 6:es
1-3, "What shall we say then? Shall we
continue in sin that grace may abound?
God forbid. How shall we that are dead
to sin live any longer therein? Know ye
not that so many of us were baptized
into Jesus Christ were baptized into his
death? Therefore, we are buried with him
by baptism into death, that like as
Christ was raised from the dead by the
glory of the Father, even so should we
also walk in newness of life."
I don't know if y'all catch this.
I don't know if you see this or
understand this.
The old man The old man is to be
crucified daily.
Meaning there is a conflict, a battle
between the house of David and the house
of Saul in every one of us.
Put a one in the chat if you can relate.
Yes, I got the house of David and I've
got the house of Saul within me.
The good that I would
that I do not and the evil that I don't
want to do that I do. Beloved, that is
the house of Saul and that is the house
of David.
There is a conflict going on
in each one of us.
The old man is being put to death. But
beloved, when you understand that
1st Samuel 3:1 tells us
by the grace of God
that the house of David gets stronger
and stronger while the house of Saul
gets weaker and weaker. Do you
understand what that's telling you?
What it's telling you, beloved, is that
as you continue to trust in Jesus and as
you continue to trust in this prophecy
that you, the house of David, the new
man, will grow stronger and stronger
while the old man will grow weaker and
weaker. The habits that you used to be
unable to kick will get kicked. You will
begin to defeat the house of Saul.
Are y'all catching this?
My slides don't seem to be working. So,
we just gonna we just y'all just going
to do without the slides for the rest of
this message. All right. The house of
David will grow stronger
while the house of Saul will grow
weaker. Now, why is this? Because the
Bible tells us in 2 Corinthians 5:17,
"If any man be in Christ, he is a new
creature. Old things are passed away.
Behold, all things are become new. Come
on, y'all. Come on. Do you understand?
Do you understand that David was
anointed to take the place of Saul?
What Saul once ruled, David is now to
take over. Do y'all Do y'all catch this?
The old man used to rule you. He used to
rule your feelings, your emotions. He
was the king of the kingdom. The house
of Saul ruled. Hey, he just says
something to you. Revenge.
Hey, that's your weakness. Follow your
weakness. The house of Saul was the
king.
But then then there was a little David
inside you that said, you know what? I
really love Jesus and I want to follow I
want to follow Jesus. A and Jesus came
into your life and anointed you and
said, "Hey, I've anointed you to take
the place of the current king." Do y'all
understand? I've anointed you to take
the place of the current Saul in your
life, the old man.
Now, don't worry. The old man, listen
now,
the old man is going to try to javeine
you.
All right, now y'all put that one in the
chat if you're like, "Oh, yeah. I have
been javelined before."
Come on, put that one in the chat. That
Oh, man. But see, beloved, here's what I
want you to understand. This is why God
gives us his word. because his word
gives us understanding. And when we have
understanding, we can then begin to walk
in that understanding. If I didn't know
that that being born again meant you're
in the house of David now and the house
of David wins, the house of David grows
stronger.
Oh, then let me start acting like it.
Let me start walking by faith in the
house of David. Let me understand now
that oh that's why the old man is trying
so hard because the old man hates the
new man. The old man hates David.
Remember, remember remember
Galatians or or I'm sorry uh again
Galatians chapter 5 verse1 14 the Bible
says for all the law is fulfilled in one
word even this thou shalt love thy
neighbor as thyself but if you bite and
devour one another take heed that you be
not consumed one of another I say then
walk in the spirit and you shall not
fulfill the lust of the flesh for the
listen y'all for the flesh lusteth
against the spirit spirit and the spirit
against the flesh and these are contrary
the one to the other so that you cannot
do the things that you would do you
understand this
the spirit and the flesh are at war with
one another. I will put enmity between
the house of David and the house of
Saul. And so beloved, this is what is
happening within us. Just remember when
Jacob and Esau were in their mother's
womb, the Bible says in Genesis 25:22,
"And the children struggled together
within her and said, and she said, if it
be so, why is it why am I thus?" And she
went to inquire of the Lord. And the
Lord said unto her, two nations are in
thy womb, and two manner of peoples
shall be separated from thy bows. The
one sha the one people shall be stronger
than the other people.
And the elder that is the one that came
first shall serve the younger.
Do do you this you guys? This thing is
all over the scriptures.
Oh, so you mean within me?
Within me there are two households that
are struggling. The house of David and
the house of Saul. The house of Saul was
older than the house of David. David was
the younger. Saul was the older.
God is saying here, listen,
I know you got struggles going on inside
you, but I need you to understand the
prophecy. The prophecy is you win. Now,
now you can tap into this prophecy by
faith, but if you don't tap into it by
faith, the prophecy doesn't work.
The only way the prophecy works is by
faith because I'm not going to force
righteousness on you.
So you have to believe by faith. By
faith that number one, I've led you into
the house of David. And number two, that
when you're in the house of David, the
house of David grows stronger and
stronger while the house of Saul grows
weaker and weaker. So now I got to walk
today saying to myself, "Yeah, the old
man is weaker today. He was weaker than
he was yesterday." Why do you believe
that? Because it's prophecy,
but it's conditional prophecy.
Meaning meaning
the prophecy is dependent on whether I
receive it or not.
Yeah. [snorts] Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
Do y'all catch this?
Do you understand? Do you understand?
In 1st Samuel 18:8, Saul was very wroth
with David and displeased with him. He
said, "They have ascribed unto David 10
thousands, and to me they have ascribed
thousands." Remember now, watch this.
David was winning more battles than
Saul.
Somebody put 10,000 in the chat, y'all.
Somebody put 10,000 in the chat. Saul,
David, whereas at first Saul was
praised, man, Saul is winning thousands.
Saul's defeated thousands and thousands.
When David comes on the scene,
oh, David is experiencing 10,000
victories.
When you understand this, beloved,
the house of David in you begins to
experience 10,000 victories. And whereas
the house of Saul had been experiencing
more victories, his victories become
less and less and less. And are y'all
following this?
It's prophecy, but it's conditional.
The prophecy is activated by faith,
which is belief.
So just like David went out there and
said, "Yep, I am a I'm fighting Goliath.
I believe I that same faith of David is
required for us in our battle against
the house of David."
2 Samuel 28:17.
And the Lord had done unto him as he
spake. For the Lord has rent the kingdom
of thine out of thine hand and given it
to thy neighbor, even to David. You
understand
the prophecy states that God has rent
the kingdom from the old man and given
it to the new man. You have to walk in
that.
You have to believe in that.
You have to You have to trust that.
Yeah. Are y'all following?
Are you catching what I'm saying?
So now, now I need to bring I need to
bring you to to an another level, a yet
deeper level.
Let's see. I'm g see if I can pull up my
slides again. Um,
hold on, hold on, hold on. All right.
So, we're going to go to 1st Samuel
chapter 24. 1st Samuel chapter 24 and
verse 4.
1st Samuel 24:4.
There we go. There we go. So,
[clears throat]
in fact, don't put that up on the screen
yet. Just hold on a second.
Do you remember in the Bible how um the
Bible says that God chose David because
David was a man after his own heart? Do
y'all remember that
David was a man after God's own heart?
So I need you to understand something
here. When when we're looking at this in
the context of the personal battle, the
house of David versus the house of Saul,
what qualifies
for the house of David is when you have
a heart after God's own heart.
Does everybody understand that? So
remember a little bit earlier, remember
a little bit earlier where we read,
watch this, uh in Galatians 5:14, the
Bible says, "For all the law is
fulfilled in one word, even in this,
thou shalt love thy neighbor as
thyself."
The heart of God is the heart of love.
Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself.
But if you bite and devour one another,
take heed that you be not consumed of
one another. And then the very next
verse, this I say then, walk in the
spirit and you shall not fulfill the
lust of the flesh. For the flesh lusteth
against the spirit and the spirit
against the flesh. In other words, to
have the heart of God means to love.
To love.
And then God says, "Hey, David is a man
after my own heart."
Now, I want you to understand the
context here
because remember Saul is actively
attempting to kill David.
And I want you to notice how David
responds. 1st Samuel 24 verse4 1st
Samuel 24:4. And the men of David said
unto him, Behold the day of which the
Lord said unto thee, Behold, I will
deliver thine enemy into thine hand, and
that thou mayest doeth unto him, as it
seemed good unto thee. Then David arose
and cut off the skirt of Saul's robe
privy.
So David could have killed Saul.
Follow along.
And David said unto Abashai, "Destroy
him not, for who can stretch forth his
hand against the Lord's anointed, and be
guiltless."
Come on, follow me again. 1st Samuel
26:11, "The Lord forbid that I should
stretch forth my hand against the Lord's
anointed, but I pray thee, take thou now
that the spear that is in thy bolster,
and the cruise of water, and let us go.
1st Samuel 24:6. And he said unto his
men, "The Lord forbid that I should do
this thing unto my master, the Lord's
anointed, to stretch forth my hand
against him, seeing he's the Lord's
anointed." Let's pause for a second.
David
is being persecuted by an enemy.
And instead of him responding,
instead of him responding, in fact, let
me let me let me just read it from the
Bible. 1 Peter chapter 3:9. Not
rendering evil for evil or railing for
railing, but contraise blessing, knowing
that you are there unto called that you
should inherit
a blessing. That's pretty interesting.
The Bible tells us that we should love
our enemies. Romans 12:17, recompense to
no man evil for evil. Provide things
honest in the sight of all men. How
about this? Matthew chapter 5 verse 44.
But I say unto you, love your enemies.
Bless them that curse you. Do good to
them that hate you, and pray for them
which is which despitefully use you and
persecute you, that you may be the
children of your father in heaven. For
he maketh the sun to rise on the evil
and on the good, and sendeth rain on the
just and on the unjust. Watch this. For
if you love them which love you, what
reward have you? Do not even the
publicans the same? And if you salute
your brethren only, do you what do you
more than others? Do not even the
publicans the same? Be ye therefore
perfect,
even as your father which is in heaven
is perfect. Now, let me break this down,
you guys. And we're almost done. We're
almost there.
[clears throat]
David
is strong in love.
Saul is weak because of hate.
Did y'all catch what I just said?
David
grows stronger because of love. David
loved Saul.
But Saul is his enemy. But David is
loving Saul.
Saul grew weaker because of his hate for
David.
Do you see the formula? Hate leads to
weakness.
Love leads to strength.
Why is this significant?
Because we're told in Revelation 12:17
that the dragon was wroth with the
woman, meaning he hates her, and went to
make war with the remnant of her seed,
which keep the commandments of God and
have the testimony of Jesus Christ. You
understand what this means? that as time
goes on, the hatred of the house of Saul
towards the house of David will grow
stronger and stronger because the house
of Saul is growing weaker and weaker,
meaning they're becoming more and more
wicked as time goes on. So,
so in in the very last generation, watch
this now y'all. So remember how God
said, "Be therefore perfect as your
father in heaven is perfect." And the
the example that is being used is loving
those who are trying to javelin you.
At the very end of time, the house of
Saul
will be so weak.
weak in righteousness,
weak in love,
weak in mercy. They will be the weakest
generation
that has ever lived. They'll have no
strength to love, no strength to do
righteousness. Absolute weak. Absolutely
weak.
Which means the level of persecution
against God's people in that time will
be like nothing the world has ever seen.
This is why the Bible says in Daniel
12:1, "And at that time shall Michael
stand at the great prince which standeth
for the children of thy people, and
there will be a time of trouble such as
never was." Are y'all getting me? Such
as never was. So the question is, if the
house of David grows stronger and
stronger, what are they going to grow
stronger in? They're going to grow
stronger in love.
And they will need to be that strong in
love because the house of Saul will be
that weak in love. Are y'all are y'all
following what I'm saying?
Are you understanding the concept here?
The Bible says in 1 John 4:18, "There is
no fear in love, but perfect love casts
out fear because fear involves torment.
He who fears has not been made perfect
in love." God says, "I need you to be
perfect." How? In love.
Saul perished, Candace, because of his
hatred.
God says, "I need the final generation
to be so perfected in love that when all
the wickedness is pointed toward them
and the javelins and the Sauls are
coming after the house of David, the
weakness of the house of David will be
matched by the strength, I'm sorry, the
weakness of the house of of Saul will be
matched by the strength of the house of
David. That's what's going to happen at
the end of time. The battle will be the
weakness of the house of Saul and the
strength of the house of David.
This is why the Bible tells us in
Colossians 3:14, "Above all these
things, put on charity, which is the
bond of perfection."
What love is the bond of perfection?
Beloved, I I fear
that many of us have boiled perfection
down to uh what time did you eat your
last meal?
We don't understand the greater picture
of perfection.
We don't understand
why love
is the bond of perfection. We don't
understand why perfect love. We don't
understand how loving our enemy and
those who despitefully use us is the
signal of being perfect as your father
which is in heaven is perfect. And I
need you to understand this now. You see
Jesus said, "If you've seen me, you've
seen the father." You following? If
you've seen me, you've seen the father.
So in order to understand the love of
the father, all we need to do is look at
the love of the son. And the best
picture that we have of the love of
Jesus is at the cross.
And you will remember that it is here at
the cross where the Bible says in first
Peter chapter 23, who when he was
reviled, reviled not again. When he
suffered, he threatened not, but
committed himself to him that judgeth
righteously.
You remember what happened at the cross?
Jesus
got javelined.
Lord, Lord, Lord, Lord.
They literally took a javelin and
pierced him in his side.
They took nails and pierced his hands
and his feet.
David escaped the javelin. Jesus didn't.
And even in being javelined,
here's what the Bible says in Luke
23:34. Then said Jesus, "Father, forgive
them for they know not what they do.
The picture of perfection
is right there at the cross.
When the Bible says the house of David
will grow stronger and stronger, when
the Bible says the house of David grew
stronger and stronger, it is a parallel
prophecy saying that God's people by the
end of time will be so imbued with the
spirit of love,
the spirit of grace and supplication
that in the face of the greatest hatred,
they will demonstrate the greatest acts
of love.
Lord,
help me
to be a part of the house of David.
If I can just get into the house of
David,
if I can just get access to the house of
I will be a part of that stream of
prophecy.
That tells me
you will grow stronger by my grace, by
my power, by my love, by my goodness.
Help me to accept that prophecy by faith
and begin to walk in it.
Help
me to realize that while Saul is, you
know, Saul was winning his 10,00ands,
now now he's down to his thousands.
Now he's down to his hundreds.
Now he's down to his tens. Lord, help
me. Help me by the grace of God to grow
stronger in my faith, stronger in my
walk with you, stronger in my devotion
to you, stronger in my study of the word
of God, stronger in all things that
pertain to righteousness.
Help me treat this as a prophecy
that I accept by faith and that I walk
in.
If it is your desire
to by faith accept the prophecy
that the house of David grew stronger
and stronger while the house of Saul
grew weaker and weaker. If it is your
desire to see the old man grow weaker
and weaker while the new man grow
stronger and stronger to where the new
man is winning his 10 thousands while
the old man is only now winning
thousands and that number will continue
to drop as you advance in the word of
God and advance in your walk of
sanctification. Then please put that
five in the chat and say pastor that is
me right there. I need to have faith in
this prophecy.
I need to walk in this prophetic future
that God has laid out for the house of
David. I see the fives in the chat. I
see the fives in the chat. Praise God.
May God bless you as you as you
internalize this truth and begin to walk
in it by faith. I'm going to make a
second appeal. There's anyone who is
watching today or that who will watch
and you're saying, you know what, I need
to fully give my life to Christ. I my
David isn't even here yet. I've been
living Saul has been the king of my life
and I now need David to be the king of
my life. I now need David to take the
place of Saul. I need Jesus to be the
rightful king in my life. And I need to
take I need to take the place of the old
man. Christ in me, the place of the old
man. And you want to make that decision
for the first time, whether that is
accepting Christ for the first time, I'm
going to ask you to put a one in the
chat. If you're saying, "I I I've
accepted Christ, but I need to be
baptized." I'm going to ask you to put
that two in the chat. I'm also going to
ask you, if either one of those are you,
number one or number two, I'm going to
ask you to reach out. We'll put the link
up at the end of this message. Reach out
and connect with us. If you want to be
baptized, if you're trying to give your
life fully to Christ, reach out, connect
with us, and we will walk you through
that process. Okay?
So, as you're putting those numbers in
the chat, I'm going to go ahead and pray
and ask the Holy Spirit to sanctify and
to bless your decision
to walk as a member of the house of
David. Okay, let us pray. Heavenly
Father,
we thank you Lord for speaking today,
for helping us to understand the truth
that has always been there. Lord, help
us to access the house of David through
the key of David which only you have.
Help us to walk into that place and by
faith
live out the prophecy
of the house of David growing stronger
and stronger as time goes on.
Thank you Lord for every decision that
has been made to walk in that house, to
be a part of that house,
to fight against the house of Saul, and
to grow stronger in faith by grace.
Lord, strengthen our walk, strengthen
our faith, and grant us the victories we
so desire.
This we pray in the precious and holy
name of Jesus. Amen. And amen.
Um we're going to go ahead and put up
this last slide so you can see how you
can connect with us. Um you connect with
us connect with us on our social media.
You can uh connect with Living Mana
online. Um if you again are interested
in in Bible study in baptism, please
email bibleworker living manana.urch.
church. Um, and again, may God bless
you. We'll also put the link in the chat
for the afterglow,
um, which will be on Mighty Network. So,
we encourage you to join Mighty Network
so you can stay informed with what's
going on with Living Mana. And again,
guys, may God bless you and keep you and
may you walk as a member of the
household of David. Amen. And amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmanaa.urch.
[music] We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
>> [music]